[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Welcome Living Mana Church family, it's
so great to have all of you here with
us. We're happy to see all of you and we
know you're viewing from all around the
world. So, we want to see where you're
viewing from. So, please put it in the
chat so we can say a special welcome to
you. And if this is your very first
time, please put a one in the chat
because we want to do a very special
welcome to you. tell you a little bit
more about Living Mana Church and what
goes on here and that we are just happy
that you are here with us today. So,
please let us know where you guys are
watching from. We're very happy for all
of you to be here.
>> Yes, we uh want to welcome you to Living
Matter Online. Uh we have uh I think an
excellent service uh in place for today.
>> Yes.
>> Um I mean we always say that but we
always believe that.
>> Well, the Holy Spirit is here so and
it's Sabbath. It's always a blessing.
>> Yes. Yes. Yes. So, welcome everyone. Uh
for anyone who is here for the first
time, please our Living Mana regulars
make them feel welcome as they put their
one in the chat.
>> Yeah, we have a one. We have a one from
Deanna Tyler from Elton, Maryland.
Welcome. Glad to have you here um with
Living Mana Church. We are a 100% online
church. We offer programs during the
week. On Mondays, we have Mental Health
Monday um that's hosted by myself and
Dr. Ricardo White. We have um doctors
and nutritionists who lead out in um
True Health Tuesday which is Tuesdays.
Wednesdays we have two different prayer
services and on Thursdays we have
programming with our young adult pastor
Lami Richardson. So we are here doing
things all throughout the week. We also
have children's programming on Sabbath
which is happening right now. LMLC kids.
So if you have kids or know someone with
kids that want to get involved um in our
online church service, uh you'll hear
more about how to do that in just a bit.
So just want to welcome you. Thank you
for being with us today. And there were
many others telling us where they're
viewing from. Uh we had Bernice from
Virginia. Welcome, Wendy Allen from
Idaho.
Yes, welcome. Happy Sabbath, Frank. Um,
I don't want to say that last name
wrong. Um, but happy Sabbath from China.
That has to be the first one. China.
That has to be the first one from China.
We have people all around the world, but
>> I think that's the first one from China.
Frank, do you are you visiting China? Do
you live in China? Um, that's great.
We're happy that you are here and if you
can't say all that for any reason, you
don't have to tell me all that, but
we're happy that you are here.
>> Amen.
>> Definitely happy. Um, let's see. I know
I've been missing some. And okay, we
have Don from OKC, Oklahoma City.
Welcome. Oh, all right. Rob Green II is
watching from Euseimde today. Beautiful,
beautiful
>> part of California. Like if you have
never been and you guys want to go to
California, you have to try to take a
visit to Euseite National Park.
Absolutely beautiful. And I feel so
spoiled because I didn't grow up right
there, but in the
youth camps
park or still is camp
indeed national park. is like, so I have
to say we were quite spoiled. Beautiful,
>> beautiful,
>> beautiful area there. Um, we're missing
some. I just saw a whole lot more that
popped up. Um, yep, we have
>> Yes, your home island where you were
born. Um, not raised but born. Um, Andre
from Toronto. Welcome to Living Mana
Church, Frank. Okay, got it. Frank, I
was about to say Frank, you can't be in
the UK and China at the same time, but
got it. You're in China right now, but
you're from the UK. All right, cool.
Welcome. Welcome.
Um, Lisa from Trinidad and Tobago,
welcome here to Living Man Church. We're
happy that you are here. Vanessa from
Texas, welcome. So glad to have all of
you here today. I want to say something
before I forget. So yesterday we
attended the inauguration service of doc
Dr. uh Brown um for at to for to be the
12th president of Oakwood University
which was an amazing service and it was
just uh great and so many people that I
you know that we saw so many people
there. Um but this is I have to share
this one thing. The one one of the
moments that stood out to me uh well the
whole service was wonderful but then
after the service I turned around uh and
I smiled at a lady just you know how you
see somebody and you greet them like hi
you know and then she looked she kept
looking at me she's like you don't
remember do you I mean she looked so
intense and I was like and I looked at
her for a little bit longer
>> and I was like Mrs. Hope she was my
English teacher junior year at Pine
Forge Academy and I had not seen her I
know since 1992 when I graduated. Um but
just the emotions that came over me were
so overwhelming because and she said
that she watches us here all the time if
you guys are wondering why I'm sharing
because I want Mrs. Holt to connect to
me by emailing me at attantontemana.urch
church uh because we didn't get to say
proper goodbye or you know you know
exchange any information or anything but
she said she watches all the time so I'm
doing this now but I have to say the
reason why it was so special is because
I remember Mrs. Hol was so kind to us
students like she really like was just
very kind and patient and she just had
this special kindness to her that really
stood out. Not to say that everybody
else was mean. I'm not saying that. No
shade. But she was very special and she
stood out. And so, um,
>> we need to always be kind to people. You
never know how long how far that will.
>> Yes. Because I remember I really
remember that. And it was
>> u especially with young people when
they're in a space because I I wasn't
converted then. Right. So
>> that spoke to me. That spoke to me and
um it was just great to see her.
>> Yeah. and that she's she's doing well.
So, please email me at tante living mana
living mana.urch because we got kind of
separated. There was a big crowd and I
we didn't get to say proper goodbyes.
So, I hope she's watching or we'll watch
later.
>> Yeah,
>> I hope.
>> Uh which, you know, bringing that up
>> that's going to tie really nicely into
our Sabbath school in which we are going
to be addressing the fruit of the
spirit.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> And just you know what it means to have
that character
>> Yes.
>> of Christ. You remember people like
that? Yes. They stick out.
>> Like I almost cried when she started
talking because I could remember how
sweet she was. The fact that she was
like, "Oh, I watch you guys' program. I
watch Living Man all the time." And she
was like, "I'm so proud of you." And
that just like it really touched my
heart. Not that I'm trying to boast or
anything, but again, she knew me as a
16, 17 year old. I wasn't converted yet.
So, I don't think she saw like, oh yeah,
she's going to go marry a pastor and be
doing ministry. That I don't think she
thought that then. But so it just but
her kindness really stood out and it's
>> it impacted my life.
>> Amen.
>> So yes, before we start our Sabbath
school
>> and we have a membership transfer, too.
Okay.
>> I wonder if we should do that first.
Let's do that first. Let's do that
first.
>> Okay. Second reading. I still think we
should have like a trumpet or something.
>> Sound effects. I said this like two,
three years ago and he laughs at me, but
I think it would be cool because we're
not in person and like we could do
applause,
drum roll, something. It's exciting
>> when people when every time somebody
joins living manage church, it's very
exciting. But we have a second reading
of someone that is very active in the
church
um and is already feels like she already
feels like a member. So this is just the
official. It's almost like when you get
baptized.
>> That's just you're already serving
Christ. You're already already following
Jesus, but you're just making it public
and official. So this is the official
>> That's right.
>> um reading to make her be
>> a living mana member. So This is the
second reading for Takara
Bumus
Otinio.
Okay, I said those right from
Indianapolis Capital City 7th Day
Adventist Church. And again, she's
already a leader in our hangouts. She uh
is just such a vibrant um person and
brings so much character and life to
everything that she does. even when she
like again after on the afterlow after
the service we have an afterglow. She's
just always just so full of energy and
life and I just love that about her.
>> So we are thrilled to have that second
reading.
>> Yep. Uh so uh we're going to entertain a
motion and a second uh to accept Takora
into fellowship at the Living Manor
online
um church. And uh again, we're we're
super excited to have her as a member.
Um
and again,
you know, I think back to uh when we
were thinking about starting this church
>> and all the questions of well, how would
a church like this work?
>> Yeah.
>> And you know, seeing it work and seeing
it work in real time.
>> Yeah.
>> Um seeing things like this happen is
just I think uh
uh testament to what God is doing
through this church and through the
members of this church. So,
>> right,
>> I just praise God for that. So, we've
got a motion. We've got a second. And uh
let's go ahead and put that seven in the
chat. Seven in the chat for
>> Yes. Oh, welcome.
>> Perfection. Yes.
>> Sabbath. Let's use that number.
>> Let's use the seven.
>> Um
>> but also, as they're putting their their
numbers in, um it was just nice to It's
always nice. Guys, I know we're here. We
love being online, but we also like to
bump into some of you, our people who
view, you know, just to meet in the
perspective. Yesterday, we got to see a
lot of people uh that are watching and
are blessed. And so, that's also very
encouraging on what God has done with
this whole ministry. It's not He and I
don't put this together. We we don't do
this alone. This is a a all hands-on
deck group effort on all on many
different levels. And the Holy Spirit is
instructing. Yeah.
>> Our lead, our guidance.
>> Yeah.
>> Guiding us. All right.
>> Yep. So, okay. Um,
>> got sevens.
>> Oh, got a lot of sevens. All right.
>> Lots of sevens. Amen.
>> Lots of sevens.
>> And, uh, politically politically
incorrect. Yes, we are fully organized.
And yes, we agree with you. It's a very
creative way to adapt to the changing
times to spread the gospel.
>> Yes.
>> So, keep us in prayer on that.
>> Actually, politically incorrect. Um, we
are the first official online church of
the Seventh Day Adventist Church. Our
church is um a church in the
Northeastern Conference. And I'm low-key
losing my voice. That's probably because
I was I wasn't talking that much last
night. You were doing all of the
talking. So, let's pray for my voice.
>> Yeah.
>> But we want to welcome This is Well, you
do it. I'm not
>> Yeah. Carrie. You're probably losing
your voice because I talked so much last
night.
>> Because the two are one.
>> I know. I don't know.
>> The two. That's cute.
>> Takora, it is passed. Welcome. Welcome.
Welcome.
>> Trumpet officially. Not that we're
welcoming you,
>> but this is just the official welcome
>> because even like during the pandemic
and when we were just when we were still
with Campbell Church, I feel like she
was online with us then. I think so.
>> And did we meet her at an army bible
camp when we were in Indianapolis at one
time?
>> I don't I think so.
>> Okay. Yes. Well, we are happy that you
are a member. You're already so active
in the church. We love the things that
you are doing and helping us with and
growing this church and for God's
kingdom. So, thank you and welcome. And
you're just going to continue to do what
you're doing and probably more.
>> Amen.
>> So, praise God. Amen.
>> All right.
>> So,
>> t-shirt
>> faith.
>> It's just faith.
>> Oh, okay. I thought it says so faith.
>> Faith. It looks like you look it looks
like oh, compared to all the other
t-shirts, this is so basic. This is not
basic. This is just this is it. And I
was thinking about it this morning. It's
like I talk about faith all the time in
different ways, but it's really God
allowing us to participate in this
supernatural journey
>> because we're believing and we're
believing fullheartedly in something
that we can't who we can't or a person
or God that we can't see,
>> right?
>> And
that's a supernatural journey that the
Holy Spirit helps us connect to and go
on. You know what I mean? And and it
it's
>> it's to do that. That's the only thing
we can do. We don't we can't save
ourselves. We can't change anything.
Yeah.
>> We can't change, you know, somebody
else. We can pray and have faith. That's
all we can do.
>> And he's like, he's like, I need I want
you to be so well trained in that
>> and just let me do all the work. And
when you it will change you and when you
come to heaven,
>> you will just
that will be your character.
>> Just spending time with God, believing
in him, and trusting him. Because that's
where Lucifer went off. He stopped
trusting. He stopped having faith that
what God was doing is best and his
position was okay and he just needed to
to be okay with that but he wasn't. So
this is what we have to learn.
>> Yeah.
>> Is faith.
>> It looks basic but it's the classroom of
our spiritual life every single day.
>> Yeah. And you know just as you were
saying I just thought of something that
I haven't thought about before because
faith is required for things that you
can't see. Mhm.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and so that term righteousness by
faith really kind of takes on a whole
new meaning because when you look at
yourself, you don't see righteousness.
>> You see rags.
>> You see,
so it's almost as if God is saying,
even though you can't see it in
yourself,
>> I need you to live it out as if it were
real.
>> Yes. which I've never really thought
about righteousness by faith like that
before.
>> Yes.
>> Um and maybe it's, you know,
>> it's righteousness by your you can't
see, but you're like, okay, you know
what I'm saying?
>> How can I be righteous? How can I do
right? How can I live right? I don't
even see how that's possible.
>> You can't see it,
>> but move ahead.
>> Move ahead
>> and faith. Walk in it
>> by faith.
>> This is the only way. see nothing in
ourselves is good
>> that God wants us to learn because with
this he can do all the other things that
we need to change us and every all the
other areas he just needs us to do this
>> so it's not basic guys
>> it's a lot
>> it's a lot so hopefully that encourages
>> that might be a sermon coming
>> okay
>> you just got a sneak peek
>> well give me credit
>> the evidence of things not seen that's
probably
>> I feel like preaching that right now you
guys the evidence of things not seen
>> you you have other you have this
I have next week.
>> You have next week.
>> Oh, wow. The evidence of things not
seen.
>> That was my in my during in my
conversion. God, that was that was my
text.
>> Yeah.
>> One of my texts.
>> I used to use that to open. Okay. It's
the whole story. But I use that as the
opening of my radio program. But yeah,
that was a
>> very powerful text. So, all right.
Sabbath school.
>> So, Sabbath school, we are going to
>> I am excited. Well, I'll tell you a pray
and then they'll see why I'm excited for
Sabbath school. Not just because of what
we're speaking about, but one other
thing. So,
>> yeah,
>> Art of War.
>> Yes,
>> we are continuing our Now, we didn't do
this last week. Uh because we
>> we took a break.
>> Yeah, we took a break and actually
addressed a separate a different issue.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and so we're coming back now to our
chapter 4 of the Christian art of war.
And for those of you that are joining uh
that haven't been with us um before or
are joining just haven't been with us in
the past few weeks, we have been going
through
a book that I wrote called The Christian
Art of War. Um it is it is modeled after
the ancient book by Sunzu called the art
of war
but it is Christian-based
and it's dealing with um
understanding and fighting against the
greatest enemy that we have which is
self. And so that's kind of how we have
been um we've been going through each
chapter and right now we're beginning on
chapter we're starting chapter four.
Yes.
>> And chapter 4 is entitled the spirit of
war. The spirit of war.
Um
and uh
we're going to go ahead and in fact
before we invite our guests, I'm just
I'm just going to read the introduction.
I'll read the introduction.
>> Okay.
>> Then we'll bring our guests on. In fact,
we need to pray first. Yes. So, do you
want to pray?
>> I'll pray.
>> All right.
>> Heavenly Father, Lord, we thank you for
this Sabbath. Thank you uh for this
topic, Lord. Thank you for all of our
viewers. And I just ask that your Holy
Spirit would be with us as we share this
information. Let it change our lives.
Help us to learn how to fight um in a
way that we will be successful, Lord, in
Jesus name, through your power. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. So, the Spirit of War
chapter begins with um with By the way,
for those of you that are asking how you
can get a copy of the book,
>> that's what I was going to say.
>> Yeah. Um, and I don't know if we could
put in the chat, we definitely will do
it at the beginning of church service,
so stay tuned if you are not already on
um, Mighty Networks, but we're releasing
the chapters. Chapter 4 is on Mighty
Networks.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, so you can all three chapters are
there. All four chapters should be there
and so you can download it when you go
to Mighty Networks.
>> Yeah. We're we're just releasing it
chapter by chapter so you don't have to
go out and buy the book. The book is
actually out of print, right? for where
I'm actually talking with Remnant right
now. Connected with them last week.
>> Cool.
>> And uh we're going to see what we can do
about getting the book back into print.
So
>> they should have never taken it out of
print. It's amazing book.
>> Yeah. But um
>> so if you hear me remnant, that's I said
that.
>> Yeah. So okay. So um each chapter begins
with a quote from a military leader.
>> And please look in the in the chat. I'm
sorry because the mighty networks is
there and you click on that sign up for
that and you can get the book or the
chapters.
>> Yeah.
>> So the quote that starts this this
chapter the spirit of war is from
Napoleon Bonapart who said he who fears
being conquered is sure of defeat.
He who fears being conquered is sure of
defeat. It it is another way of of
really saying that when we fight we have
to fight without fear. Mhm.
>> We have to have the spirit of war, not
the spirit of fear. God has not given
you a spirit of fear, but of power and
of love and of a sound mind. So um so
let me read the introduction, short
introduction, but it says, "One of the
most essential preparations for a
warrior is the preparation of his
spirit. His attitude must be imbued with
certain attributes vital to warfare."
The Christian warrior is no different.
Without the right spirit, he is doomed
already. That spirit is the spirit of
God given to make us mighty. In
Ephesians 3:16,
it says that he would grant you
according to the riches of his glory to
be strengthened with might by his spirit
in the inner man. 2 Timothy chapter 1
verse 7 says, "For God has not given us
a spirit of fear but of power." This
spirit, the spirit of power empowers,
The Bible tells us, "Walk in the spirit
and you shall not fulfill the lust of
the flesh." Galatians 5:16.
>> As we learn to walk in the spirit of
power, we are granted power over the
flesh.
>> But go back to that piece. I'm sorry.
And I where it says
power
>> the spirit of power and powers.
>> Yes.
I'm That's That's very deep right there.
Mhm.
>> I know we're not we haven't brought it
yet, but that's very deep right there.
>> Yeah.
>> I I talk about that with my not with my
clients like
>> what I'm giving them telling them to do
their affirmations and stuff
>> like I don't like you're going to feel
like even if you have to like fake like
you don't believe like you're feeling
like this is awkward. I don't believe
this really about myself, but eventually
if you keep saying it you do. It's like
you want to even though you feel like
you're weak and you can't do this. Yeah.
>> Like
>> step forward in faith
>> and just act like
>> Yeah. Faith. You don't see it.
>> Yeah.
>> But walk in it.
>> Walk in it. That's powerful.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, as we learn to
Yeah. As we learn to walk in the spirit,
we are granted power over the flesh.
This is indeed the spirit of war.
Galatians 5:17 says, "For the flesh
lusteth against the spirit, and the
spirit against the flesh, and these are
contrary, the one to the other, so that
you cannot do the things that you
would." So, I'm going to just stop right
there. We're going to pause right here.
>> We're going to bring our guests on and
we'll start our discussion just on that
little part that that I just read. So,
guests,
>> welcome.
>> Welcome.
>> Yay. Welcome, guys.
Look at that. Terry, you tricked me.
I And um because I thought you weren't
going to be on and I was gonna when I
said, "Oh, I'm so excited for this one."
Not that I'm not excited to see you,
Terry. I'm always excited to see you,
but I thought we were have
>> young adults, but that's okay. They they
outnumber
>> you. Us. I am young or even.
There's three, but it's okay. Ladies,
welcome.
So, good to see you guys. Um, we can't
hear you guys.
>> Yeah, if anybody's talking, we cannot
>> We can't hear you. So,
somebody talk and then I'll let you know
that we can't hear you. Yep, we can't.
I'm not hearing. So, tech team,
>> uh, let us know what Oh, there it is. I
think we can hear. Let me see. Somebody
talk.
Yes, that's me.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. I can hear you. I can hear you guys.
>> Well, I'm Thank you for Maybe I didn't
see my text. Maybe you text me again,
Terry, after I thought you weren't going
to be here. But welcome, Terry. So, good
to see you here. Glad that you're
feeling better.
>> Hey, Amen. Good to be here.
>> Okay.
Um, and ladies, so good to see all three
of you.
Welcome. Are you guys excited to talk
about um chapter 4?
>> Yes. Yes,
>> definitely.
>> Okay, for those who may just be joining
us for the first time, why don't you
guys just say just all you have to say
is where your name and that's it. So
they'll know like just say who just say
your name, introduce yourself.
>> I'm Melinda.
>> Hi, I'm Michaela.
>> Hi, I'm Kazia.
>> All right.
Yes. All right, guys. Kazia, Melinda,
>> and everybody knows who Terry is
already.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, Terry still say hi,
Terry. Maybe I'm the young one.
>> The first there's a first- timer here,
so maybe they she doesn't know.
>> Yes. I Well, I am Brother Terry. I am
the prayer team leader here. But, uh,
I'm also the young one here today, and
I'm looking forward to learning from
these beautiful ladies today. So, praise
God.
>> You said you're the youngest.
>> Yes, I'm the young one today.
>> All right. The young one. All right,
ladies. We're excited to hear what you
have to say. And brother Terry, of
course, we're also hear what you have to
say. But um yes, I mean, I know you
heard the introduction. You probably
already had read that. We want to hear
some of the things that stood out to you
in the beginning of chapter 4 um for
Yeah. for the Christian Art of War. So,
anyone can go first.
>> Um maybe I can go first. Um what stood
out to me um in this specific
introduction was the part about the
combination and it really stuck out to
me that Ko said to every temptation
there is a code a combination which if
used with power will provide a way to of
escape
>> and that's just so powerful of knowing
that
>> we have a combination in in escaping
temptation.
>> Yeah. So they they so our audience may
not know what the what the combinations
what is it what do you mean
combinations? Do you want to try to
explain that or um what do you think?
>> Um yeah sure. Um so we were talking
about the fruit of the spirit which
we'll dive into that later but um the
nine spirits we're talking about they
form every possible religious
combination. You know, combination is
used sometimes on locks and um to open
locks. And we were talking about how
these um these fruits of the spirits can
be a type of combination and we can use
them to fight temptation.
>> Yeah.
>> So, so in other words, in some
temptations,
um you need
love.
>> In others, in order to overcome it, you
need joy. M
>> um in some you need a combination of
peace
>> and longsuffering, right?
>> So the way that I the way that I uh
explain it is that
>> in
in Wing Chong, the martial art that I
used to take, you're you practice a
form, right? And you're doing all these
moves.
You do them in form and you do it every
day.
>> When you actually get into a fight,
you're not actually going through the
form. What is the first move? What is
the second move?
>> You actually have to be ready to use a
combination of movements depending on
however you're being, you know, attacked
or whatever. So, when we talk about
these combinations, the fruit of the
spirit represents every possible
combination that one can use to overcome
a temptation.
Nine. Go ahead.
>> I was going to say,
>> go ahead. Go.
>> Nine. Let me finish with this. Nine
different fruit.
>> What are the combinations that are
necessary? There's a combination
that is available for every possible
attack that the Christian faces,
spiritual attack that the Christian
faces.
>> The fruit of the spirit. The
combinations come from the fruit of the
spirit. And the combination might look a
little different for
>> in every tri in every temptation.
>> And it might be different for you than
it it is for me.
>> That's right.
>> But victory,
>> the combination equals victory for each
person with each Yep.
>> temptation. Yep.
>> That is so that's so powerful. I see why
it stood out to you so much.
>> So that's just like exciting.
>> Yeah. It might be three. Okay. I need
these three fruit to overcome, you know.
>> Yeah. to overcome this issue and then
the next time around I need f sometimes
you need all nine.
>> Oh yeah. Mercy.
>> And
>> in marriage and raising kids you need
all
>> raising kids you need all nine.
>> And in raising kids, right?
>> Not that you ladies know anything about
that, but that younger one up in the
corner, he knows all about that.
>> So good. Excellent. And I think that's a
powerful
um one of the to me one of the powerful
points of this whole approach to the
spirit of war is the combinations.
>> Um which will
>> I think we'll get more into later as we
get deeper into the chapter.
>> Um okay
>> and maybe just highlighting the what the
fruit maybe there's people on there who
are like oh the fruit of the spirit I've
heard of that but maybe they don't have
them all memorized or maybe they never
heard it at all. Yeah.
>> Do you want to just mention
>> so uh the fruit of the spirit, love,
joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness,
goodness, faith, meekness, and
temperance,
>> right?
>> And I said,
>> yeah, so these are the nine fruit. So
some people say fruits, some people say
fruit. In other words,
>> these are all these are nine different
aspects of the same fruit. Some people
say there are nine different fruits, but
either way you look at it, these are
this is what makes up the character of
Christ,
>> right? And so
under understanding how each one of
these work, which is what we do in this
chapter, we go through each fruit
>> and
you know look at it in detail. What does
it mean to have love, joy, peace? Why
these why are these things necessary
um to understand and to master as we try
to learn how to fight against self
>> and longsuffering really is patience
when you're
>> I'm just thinking like
>> in the in the role that
>> like I just I mentioned marriage like
you have to I mean that's a huge
>> huge characteristic or fruit that you
need and raising children.
>> Yeah. I will say this again. Yeah,
>> I I will say this again and then I'mma
jump because we've been talking.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah, ladies.
>> We're going to bring up we promise.
>> Um
the the nine the combinations
you can't learn the combinations till
you first learn the moves,
>> right? So, how do we learn the move of
love? How do we learn the move of peace?
How do we learn the move?
>> Somebody said they want a sermon on the
combination. Yeah. How do we learn the
movement of longsuffering? Each one of
those has to be practiced in and of
itself, right? So, it's the form. When I
tell you about when we practice the
wings for it's the form, right? It's
>> there's this move and then this move and
then this move. So, you're doing these
moves. It think of these the love, joy,
peace, longsuffering as moves, right?
They're independent moves.
But when the fight comes
the combin you can't just do a move and
then be like all right done.
>> It's combinations.
>> Right.
>> Right. And you you're not going to know
the combinations if you don't know the
moves itself. All right. Go ahead. I see
>> something here.
>> Can I add? Okay. I would like to say to
that like what you just said pastor was
how do you learn to do the moves? And
now, maybe this is just me cuz I'm like
really social, but like
>> I think to learn to do the moves, you
got to hang out with somebody who knows
those and knows when to use them.
>> And not just like in the Christian walk
as an individual Christian, but just
also like just Jesus cuz like he knows
how to which moves in which scenario and
what maneuver, you know? So, I think
hanging out with Jesus, hanging out with
someone who displayed these moves
regularly is probably the best learn.
>> Amen.
>> It's his spirit after all.
>> Say that.
>> Amen.
>> Michaela, say, can you say that again?
>> Uh, it's his spirit after all.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> That's right.
>> It's the Holy Spirit. Yes. You're
absolutely Yes. Amen to both of you to
what you said. So he gives us that
spirit
for us to learn to be like him
>> because even Okay, go ahead.
>> No, I was just going to say and watching
him. So remember, I think we've been
talking about this in the in our
previous studies again, speaking of the
art of war
>> um in in those oldtime martial arts
movie, they're watching the the the
tiger and learning to copy the tiger.
They're watching, you know, the monkey.
They're watching these different animals
and then you got these fighting styles
for the Christian. The fighting style is
lamb style.
>> That is a fighting style.
>> Actually, it's two fighting styles.
>> Lamb.
>> It's lamb style and it's lion style,
>> right?
>> And
we are we are good in everyone is
naturally good in both of those styles
because we're good in the wrong way.
We're like lions against other people
>> and lambs to ourselves, right?
>> So we just whatever self wants
other people we're lion style all day
long.
>> Jesus is trying to flip it,
>> right? So like so that we're lions
against self
>> and like lambs towards other people.
>> Yes. So in watching lion style, in
watching you know lamb style,
>> lamb style is going to be seen in the
cross, right? In watching lamb style,
watching what does it mean to humble
yourself? What does it mean to submit?
What does it mean uh um uh to follow the
lamb? You're actually studying the
spirit of the lamb. And oh, these are
the com these are the movements of lamb
style.
And remember, like here's the thing,
guys. Like
when when you were studying Wing Chong,
you had to practice every day. We got up
thinking, "All right,
>> I want to get a chance to practice." You
know, we would look for opportunities to
practice. As Christians, are we looking
for opportunities to practice the moves?
All right. How can I practice love
today? How can I practice peace today?
How can I practice longsuffering? And
the more we practice,
>> the better we get.
>> Yes.
Yeah. I love this so much. It just well
because it again this is I mean this the
my clients that
do the best and make change
quickly
>> are the ones who are intentional about
using the tools and practicing what they
need like with the affirmations and
their uh every day three times a day and
their thoughts begin to change and their
behavior their feelings change their
behavior changes and they make
>> rap their changes is is rapid. And so
like if we practice every day and be
consistent with that,
we will um we will be more effective in
our spiritual fight. Yeah. Against
ourselves, which is the enemy.
>> Yep.
Um
>> Amen.
>> Go ahead, Terry. Were you gonna jump in
and say something?
>> Yeah. Yeah. I liked in the beginning
when we first started, you you mentioned
uh kung fu theater,
you know, and uh a lot of us, at least
young men anyway, used to watch a lot of
kung fu theater and try to emulate
everything we saw. I had a whole lot of
lumps upside my head trying to do things
I saw in kung fu theater. But I thank
God that the Bible is like the perfect
theater. We find the example of these
combinations. And Kazia brought
something beautiful out. I remember the
first time I saw the combination of
faith and patience in Hebrews. I think
it was Hebrews 6 uh 12. It says that you
be not slothful but followers of them
who through faith and patience inherit
the promises. And if you guys know my
testimony, I had to learn that uh really
learn that being on vacation for so
long. Faith and patience. had to hold on
to faith, you know, and walk it out.
Even though there was no evidence in my
circumstances at the time to show that
God was going to come through the way he
said he was going to come through. But I
thank God for, you know, through his
spirit. He taught me to just hold on and
be ready because the blessing is going
to come and you got to be in the
attitude of faith when it does or you're
going to miss your opportunity.
>> So, uh,
>> I thank God for that combination and
thank Kaz for bringing that out today.
>> Yeah. So, I think I I think what's
important uh for us to really grasp is
recognizing the moves when we do them,
>> right? Recognizing, all right, wow, I
just did a faith move. I just did a love
move. I just did a peace move.
>> Right? And as you're I think as we train
our minds
to recognize the move
um
we learn to identify with move so that
>> when
when we
when you first start practicing a move,
it's it's robotic.
Um it's not fluid.
>> It's almost forced. Mhm.
>> But the longer you practice the move,
>> the more it becomes um muscle memory.
>> Yes.
>> Right.
>> It becomes reflexive.
>> And that's what we're trying to get.
We're trying to get we're trying to
practice the move so much
>> that it be we're not thinking about it
anymore. We're not thinking. We're just
doing.
>> You just want to be so locked in.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's a mental train. I mean, I'm I
know. I I mean, I have so many I know
therapy thoughts. That's where my brain
goes. Like, this is
>> I see it.
>> Yeah. It's just my
>> all over your face here. I just
>> But it's exciting. It's I I don't know.
I get excited off of off of off of this
because to me, this is the exciting part
>> of the gospel.
>> Yeah. Because we all know that we have
temptations and sin that we deal with
and we just, you know,
>> the enemy wants us to feel so beat up
and feel like, oh, you there's nothing
you could do about it. I'm always, you
know, you're always going to give into
this. You might get victory sometimes,
but you're not. You know what I'm
saying? But this is so hopeful
>> and like we're putting our faith, the
strength of all of this, if we just
focus, the strength of all of this is
coming from God that it's possible.
>> Yeah. To me, this is the reason why to
be a Christian.
>> There's really to live in this world and
to live with all the things that we deal
with and all the the sadness, the
craziness, the everything. Um, it's like
this is actually this is this right here
is what makes Christianity so
attractive.
>> Yes, Jesus.
>> Amen.
>> Jesus dying on the cross for us,
>> but he died so that this would be
possible for us.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. He is he is the great grandmaster.
>> Yeah. He has not left us down here
>> to just deal with stuff on our own and
just be miserable.
>> He he's a grandmaster that that came to
teach us how to fight.
>> Yes.
>> And
he lived it. 33 years of example.
>> He lived it and then exemplified it on
the cross.
>> Yes.
>> And so the cross becomes that's the
place where we go to train.
>> Yes. So, you know,
>> we're hearing some kind of noise in the
background, like banging or something.
I'm not sure.
>> And maybe only we hear it. I don't know
if they hear it.
>> No, they're they they hear
>> Oh, they're saying that?
>> Yeah.
>> Um, so,
um,
in Wing Chong, the way that you practice
is on a wooden dummy.
It it's a it's a wooden it's literally a
wooden a wooden dummy with arms sticking
out
>> and you your your moves are on that
dummy and I'm just you and as we were
talking just now I just thought wow the
the cross
is where
um
the cross is where we practice as
Christians.
>> We practice on the cross.
>> Yes.
>> Right. That is
that is our wooden training tool.
>> And the more we practice on the cross,
the better we become at lamb style.
>> Yes.
>> The better we become at lion style.
>> Um
which means the better we become at the
nine moves of the spirit.
>> We can just call it that. The nine moves
of the spirit.
>> Yes.
>> Right.
Some of us may be fluent in one move and
weak in a whole bunch of others,
>> right? We may have patience,
>> but when that patience runs out,
>> if that patience runs out, love is out
the window, joy is out the window,
right? So, we've got to learn how to
become strong in all
>> nine movements,
>> right? You can't be a master in one and
pour into others. You're not a master at
all.
>> Right? We have to learn how to master
them all. Which means we got to practice
every day. Every day. Okay.
>> Every day. Intentional.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. We go we there's things we
>> I don't know. This is again having my my
mind is really spinning. I know we got
to bring in our we want our other guests
to be able to share too, but it's like
we focus on our focus should be this. We
focus on everything else in the day.
what we put the highlight on everything
else. Work, school, children, husband. I
mean, you guys are all important, but
this is the main focus. And then we're
still going to do all of those other
things and but we'll do them much
better. Yeah.
>> When our focus
>> is right here in doing this.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um
>> it shouldn't be a sidebar like, okay, I
had a little devotional thing in the
morning. Okay, I prayed last night or I
prayed before I meal. I prayed in the
car before I went, you know what I mean?
It's like,
>> no. Can you imagine how peaceful the
world would be if if more people
practiced the nine moves of the spirit?
>> If more people practice this this
martial art
>> lamb style
>> if people knew what it what it what it
was to practice love, joy, peace,
longsuffering, right?
>> And in fact, I'm going to do that. I'm
going to
>> We got to get to We're talking and our
guests are like I'm sorry. We're sorry,
guys.
>> We're coming. We're bringing you back.
Put in the chat
>> how can you actively practice love,
>> joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness,
goodness, faith, meekness, temperance.
Just if you have an idea, put it in the
chat. We're going to be looking at them.
But, okay.
>> Uh, guess.
>> Yeah, I'll save my
>> Anything else you want to you want to
add in um to what what we've been
talking about so far?
So something in the chapter and
connected to this that really stood out
to me.
So this method of fighting with the
spirit of Jesus with this lamblike or
lionlike spirit, it's like
it's absolutely so different from how
self would fight or
just anything else in the world really.
these principles of the spirit, it's
just so different. Like fighting with
peace, things like that,
the past is insane. And then this is not
only what we're fighting with, it's what
we're fighting for because it's so
different.
>> And so that was something I think I
really loved.
>> Amen. Amen, Michaela. And it's like
>> when you say fighting with using peace,
it's because you know, you know, I was
just thinking it kind of I'm glad you
said that because it kind of goes with
what I wanted to say. Um our practice
like you're practicing like
with
God and the spirit every day because
you're going to go out in the world and
have to deal with things. So this is a
term that people say or young people
say, oh because people may come at you,
they say they may come at you sideways.
That's what they say. that means like
they're coming at you with the wrong
attitude or they're confronting you or
something. But when you respond with
peace,
>> you've won.
>> You've won. You've gotten the victory
because your response was you didn't
respond back to them sideways as they
say. Um, and you would probably win the
person too to respect you or just to be
like you would diffuse diffuse the
situation and they would be like, "Wow."
You know, it would make them want to
think like,
who are they connected to or how are
they responding that way? Because I know
what I said should have had a different
response. Do you see what I'm saying?
Like you're actually being a witness to
the person and you're winning for
yourself as well because your training
had prepared you to be able to overcome
that temptation.
>> Yeah.
>> I hope that makes sense.
>> Yeah. Soft answer wrath.
>> Yes. Amen. Amen. I don't know if that
was Melinda or Michaela, but Amen.
Let me uh
>> real quick, Michaela, is that a What's
on your bed? Is that a dog?
>> Yeah, my dog is in the back.
>> I saw it. I was like, is that a blanket?
I It's so fat and fluff. I mean, it's
fluffy. I love animals like that. Okay,
so that's what I was like while you were
talking. I was like, is that her dog
being so good? Like I was like, but I
didn't see him or her move. So, I was
like, maybe that's like I was like,
that's cool. Very obedient, good dog.
Very pretty dog from what I can see.
Okay, sorry guys. Go ahead. funny. I'm
gonna I want to read um a little bit
more of this section because I think
it's it's just really
uh stated in a way to help us
understand. So, let me read um
these nine spirits are the basic
building blocks of righteousness. They
are the sum total of the character of
the Holy Spirit. The spirit received in
the heart produces within us a spirit
identical to its own. The nine spirits
form every possible righteous
combination that can be formed. A
combination is described as a set of
movements or actions. The word is also
used the word is also used to describe a
code which opens a lock. The nine
spirits of the the nine spirits of the
spirit are essential for the warrior to
perform through God's grace the correct
combination or set of moves when
confronted with temptations.
Um
these these thoughts, feelings and
actions will consist of a combination of
one or more of the nine fruit of the
spirit. To every temptation there is a
code, a combination which if used with
power will provide a way of escape. When
one is confronted with temptation, he or
she is often um overcome because they
cannot perform through God's grace the
right combination of thoughts, feelings
and actions that will yield the path of
victory over the temptation. The mind
shortcircuits in the midst of temptation
and is paralyzed by it. Just when joy is
needed followed by longsuffering the
mind seems unable to grab hold of these
attributes
for other for others the mind is aware
of the combination needed but there is a
lack of power to carry out the action.
We know to to do good but do it not.
>> Either way the combination of
righteousness has not been fully carried
out and we are left trapped in sin as a
result. Mhm.
>> These nine spirits then become the focal
point of the warrior for right of
righteousness. His success or failure
will be in proportion to his mastery of
these attributes. Failure to master
these nine attributes produces or
reveals a warrior's weak spots. They are
in reality only nine weak spots for a
warrior. Nine weak spots for a warrior.
They are failure in one or more of these
spirits. These nine weak spots are the
target of every assault from self.
Eliminate the weak spots and self will
become virtually powerless.
>> Amen to that. And I want to I don't want
us to miss this opportunity.
Um but you know one of our most recent
members who have become a member
Jonathan um Heasley is asking he just
said I need prayer guys. And he put it
in the chat as you guys can see big
time. I feel a pulling away happening
and I don't like it. And I just want us
to pray for him right now.
>> Yeah, let's let's heavenly father, we
want to lift Jonathan to you, Lord. And
um we're not sure what's going on with
him or what the what the spiritual
conflict is, Lord, but I pray that you
would just empower him, Lord. I pray
that the spirit of your spirit, Lord,
the spirit of of the lamb will just
enter into his soul, Lord. Enter into
his body. And
>> Lord, just um
>> protect him and keep him from the
enemy's uh thoughts, suggestions,
feelings. Lord, surround him with the
nine fruit fruits of the spirit.
>> Amen. Lord, and give him the right
combination even now to overcome this
this attack from the enemy.
>> We pray this in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Um All right. So,
>> Amen.
>> Um I I'll open the floor for any
comments on what I just read.
you know,
>> the weak spots,
>> pastor and first lady,
>> go ahead. Yeah, if and and kind of along
with what Jonathan just said, kind of
what Michaela said, you know, last night
I was really thinking about this a lot
and um we're all familiar with Sister
White's uh councils to the church, her
closing words uh where she said that uh
in in reviewing our past history and
having traveled over every step of
advance to our present standing, I can
say, "Praise God as I see what the Lord
has wrought. I am filled with
astonishment and with confidence in
Christ as leader. We have nothing to
fear for the future except we shall
forget the way the Lord has led us and
his teaching in our past history. And as
I was reading that and meditating on
that, I was thinking about this fruit of
the spirit that we're talking about. I
know you wrote this book in um 2012, I
believe.
>> And it's amazing that God gave you that.
And we're living in a time right now.
Sean Cox used to talk about we're living
in an upside down world. But to the
world, the kingdom of God seems upside
down. You know, they're drunk with the
spirit of wrath. And we're now having to
learn the characteristics of Christ, the
the the the fruit of the spirit to
combat the evil in the world. And and
and and you know, I listened to brother
John's prayer request just now. He says
he feels like he's being pulled away.
But but brother and anyone else that's
probably feeling some of that same stuff
today. Uh God is leading us right now
right where we need to be. I am thankful
for it and confident that at all we got
to do is allow him to just conquer our
hearts. And that's the thing too. You
said in the beginning, he who fears
being conquered is already conquered.
And and and that's the thing. We don't
want to let Jesus really just conquer us
because we don't trust and we don't see
it. But like you said in the beginning,
pastor, righteous by faith is he has
declared it. He's spoken it over us. and
what God has promised it's there and and
sure the feelings are there and but the
higher reality is the fact that we can
trust him and lean into him right now
while he's doing what he's doing and and
I'm really thankful and excited about
what we're talking about and that
weakness that we might feel in one area
I don't feel like I can hold on I don't
feel that I can I can hang in there but
he's got us and so uh just wanted to say
that word of encouragement to Jonathan
anybody else that might be feeling Hey,
you know, I I'm I'm in a weak spot right
now. I'm feeling like I'm fade. I feel
like I'm slipping. I've been there, you
know, in the lion's den and felt like,
Lord, I can't go another day. I can't
hold on. And just when I felt like, you
know, I I couldn't make it. Jesus, he
stepped in. And I'm talking about in
prison where it's real, where it's
volatile. There are things that happened
there that I saw. I won't even mention
because I don't want to glorify the
devil's kingdom. But I will say this,
God is faithful and good, beloved. He
will keep you and he will bring you
through. You can hold on. You can make
it, beloved.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> I was uh I was just thinking, you know,
about
actually working out
um in the gym.
>> Your favorite thing to do besides
studying the Bible?
>> Thing to do. And one of the things that
you know you're always encouraged to do
when you work out in the gym is to focus
on your weak your weak points.
>> Yeah.
>> What is your weakest point?
lock in on that and make it a strong
point.
>> And then and then okay, what's what's
the next weakest point?
>> All right, let me now that I'm not
worried about that weak point anymore.
Let me go look at my next weakest point
and let me strengthen that. Let me focus
and lock in on that and strengthen that.
>> So, we were just talking about weak
spots, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And for some people, the weak spot is
love. For others, the weak spot is,
>> you know, is is patience. Mhm.
>> For a lot of us, the weak spot is all
nine of them,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> Pick a weak spot and start to focus on
that.
>> Yes.
>> And say, "Lord, get me stronger here.
>> If I can get if I have nine weak spots
and I can move it down to eight weak
spots,
>> okay, it's a it's a little burden lifted
because I'm not worried about this thing
anymore."
>> When I say priority,
>> prioritizing the weak spots,
>> you're not trying to
fight them all at once, right? I guess
and again, you know, I always have to
compare it back to therapy, but uh when
clients come in and be like, "Yeah, this
is going on and this is going on and
this." I'm like, "Look, okay, we let's
let's take the top the number one thing
that you're dealing with." That is the
biggest issue and let's deal with one
thing at a time. Like you can't deal
with all of that at the same time. You
have to just go amen, you know, one by
one. And
>> yeah, you can definitely do that. Yeah.
>> In this fight, for sure.
>> Focus on the weak spot.
>> I'm just impressed to say,
>> you know what, one of the
One of the I just wanted to go with you
on that weak spot thing because when I I
learned a lesson about the fruit of the
spirit and it doesn't say fruits, it
says fruit because it's one spirit and
it's all him. And when you focus on the
one, you're actually plugging into the
same spirit. He'll strengthen you
throughout. So
>> focusing on the one sometimes is just
the thing he wanted us to do, you know,
and then he
>> pulls us and strengthen us in the other
areas. Yeah,
>> I just real quick just felt impressed
for uh brother Jonathan. Um, I'm not
sure if you're a part of uh LOCC's men's
ministry, but I want to encourage you if
you're not, I I don't I'm not aware, but
if you're not to to get involved because
there, you know, it's a smaller
community of men where I believe it
could be very um impactful for you and
very encouraging and a very safe space
um that, you know, I think that would be
a blessing. And for the women's
ministry, same thing. if you know, get
into that community of women that can
help you um in this where you all are,
you know, dealing with the same things.
You're you're just fighting, you know,
you're all wanting to learn the
different tools that can help you fight
um in this in this walk that we're in
and get these fruits of the spirit. So,
that's just an encouragement to men and
ladies to get involved because I really
think that community will be a blessing
to you. So, Jonathan, I'm encouraging
you to do that.
>> So, yes. Anybody else have any other
thoughts? Our guest, ladies.
So, I don't know how this would relate
to um the like practicing moves and
stuff, but this week
it was my mom actually that kind of made
me aware of this. She said, she came to
me and she said, "Wow, I just realized
that Cain offered his fruits
>> and Abel offered the lamb."
>> And I think it's really important,
>> especially Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait. Don't say anymore. Don't say
anymore cuz I don't want you to tell me
cuz I'm going to preach that and I just
need you to like not say anything.
>> Stop cuz she might
>> I want Listen, I just want the joy. I
want the joy of like discovering it for
myself.
>> No, no, no, no. Melinda,
>> go ahead. I was just He's joking. He's a
jokester. Continue on, please.
>> Okay. Okay. Fine, fine.
>> Go, go, go, go.
>> Yeah. Well, anyways, I think it's it's
important to while we're fighting self
to not forget that we're not supposed to
be offering these fruits because these
fruits and she said something else
interesting. She said that as soon as
you cut a fruit off the vine, it's
doomed to die.
>> Ah,
>> and Jesus said, "Remain in me, cuz I'm
I'm the vine."
>> So when we take these fruits, disconnect
them from Jesus, from his spirit, and be
like, "Oh, great. These are my fruits.
I'm going to present them to God." He's
like, "Uh, this is a
>> wow.
>> This is no good.
>> You're presenting dead fruit. Wow.
You're presenting.
>> Wow. And it's
>> it really brings attention to how well
even like you can't have fruit without
the vine. And if you remove them from
the vine, they're worthless.
>> Wow. Praise God.
>> Beautiful.
The chat's going The chat's going wild.
They're like powerful.
First they said, "Let her talk." And
then they like, "Yeah, fire." Wow. Like,
yeah. I don't know. You guys probably
can't see the chat, but it's it's going
it's going off right now.
>> I got like like four sermons already
just from
>> this to
>> Listen, guys, you don't have to let him
preach all you guys.
>> Yeah. No, no, no. You guys need to
preach it too. You need your platform.
And
>> that's right.
>> Okay. I'm doing like a spoiler alert. We
are working on, just for you guys to
know, we haven't chosen a date yet, but
we are going to have a completely young
adult or youth Sabbath where they're
doing everything from Sabbath school to
prayer to introductions to the sermon.
>> That is happening this year before the
year is up. We haven't chosen chosen the
date yet,
>> but you will see these young ladies
involved in it and some other of our uh
youth as well. So definitely when we we
mention the date, mark your calendar
because it's going to be amazing.
>> Yeah.
>> Praise God.
>> So I will just tie into that. Let me tie
into that that
it is the practice at the cross that
produces the fruit.
>> Amen.
>> It is the practice at the cross. This is
where we behold the lamb which takes
away the sins of the world. It is
connection to that cross that will end
up producing the fruit.
Pulling your thought together. That's
if we're trying to produce our own
fruit, it's already there.
>> It's already dead.
>> So, you know, I'd asked earlier, what
are some ways that we can practice the
fruit, right? Um, let me ask that
question because we're we're about to
get into the the In fact, let let's do
How much time do we have?
>> We have like 15 more minutes.
>> Let's let's move to the fruit of love.
That's
>> that's all we going to cover.
>> That's all. That's all.
>> And might just And might just Yeah. I
was about to say we going to probably
pick up on love next week.
>> Yeah.
>> But okay.
>> So So let me let me read a little bit of
this section. It's a short section, but
I think there's a lot to talk about. The
spirit of love is a product or fruit of
the spirit of war against the flesh. The
warrior's strength and victories will be
in proportion to his mastery of this
spirit. This is the love the warrior
must possess for his master and lord.
Love is a powerful force. Song of
Solomon 8:7 says, "Many waters cannot
quench love,
neither can the floods drown it. If a
man would give all the substance of his
house for love, it would utterly be
condemned.
Through love, the warrior is willing to
give all everything that he has. Our
general tells us, "Greater love has no
man than this, than a man lay down his
life for his friends. You are my friends
if you do whatever I command you,
whatsoever I command you." Mastery of
the spirit means a willing to lay our
lives down for Jesus. It is in essence
power in the face of temptation to be
willing to crucify self rather than
betray Jesus.
Not only should he possess a love for
his master, he should possess a love for
his country, the kingdom of heaven.
Some of y'all thought I was going to say
another place.
Patriots of heaven.
>> The sons of this world have sacrificed
themselves for the love of an of an
earthly country. The sons of heaven
should be moved with a love for their
country as higher than the heavens are
above the earth. The kingdom of heaven
must be our battlecry, our cause to die
for. Finally, the warrior must must have
a love for righteousness. Like his God
in general, he must love righteousness.
Hebrews 1:9.
He must adore it, be emotionally
connected to it, moved by it, enamored
with it. In loving all that is good,
holy, and true, he is equipped with an
essential part of the combination of
righteousness. Weakness in this spirit
will result in certain failure. Where
there is no love, there is no desire to
stand. We stand and defend in proportion
to our love for something or someone.
>> That's the love section. Amen.
>> Um, it points to the idea of being
willing to die rather than betrayed.
>> Willing to die
>> um to lay oneself down
>> rather than break rank with the Lord.
>> Amen. So
>> Joseph is such a great example of that.
>> Say that again.
>> Joseph was such a great example of that.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Like he was tempted for real.
like on a level that
a lot of men fall.
>> But he's like, "But how can I
>> do this thing against God?"
>> Yeah.
>> It was the love.
>> It was his love for God.
>> Yeah.
>> His love for
>> his love for Jesus. His love for the for
the
>> for the divine
>> that moved him
>> right
>> away from a counterfeit love.
>> Yes.
>> Right. So
the question for us is
how do we
Jonathan Mighty Networks if you're if
you're talking about Mighty Networks um
that's not an issue. So if you're having
trouble joining that we'll connect that
you shouldn't be having that issue at
all. uh anybody can join it
>> and especially the small I don't know
what he's I don't know what platform
he's talking about talking about for
men's group small group no
>> yeah I'm not sure
>> there's no there's nothing that cost
here at living church there's no cost
for anything
>> um okay so the question comes back to
how can I practice love
>> and I want to see in the chat what are
some ways
>> that you could practice So
just just think about it. What are some
ways okay today love is my weakness.
What are some things I can do to to to
demonstrate or to practice the art
of love? Love fighting.
>> I'm thinking in my head. I mean, I'm
thinking,
>> what is something you could do on a
practical level that shows love to a
stranger, love
>> to your children, love to your spouse,
love to an enemy,
>> I think that Well, I already said,
>> All right. Well,
>> hold on, Cole. Hold on one second.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Oh, no, no, no. Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Okay. I mean, I already said it earlier,
but I think like in the marriage and in
raising kids, like the thing that
the way you can practice love is using
longsuffering, which and that's
patience. And that's not and
longsuffering means like
you're suffering because maybe your
spouse didn't speak to you kindly. So, I
mean, your reaction would want to be
like, "Okay, I'm not going to be kind to
you either." But you're going to
practice longsuffering. So, it's like,
"Okay, that wasn't kind." And it's never
kind. Never. I want to be clear on this.
I don't want someone to feel like, "Oh,
well, I just have to be longsuffering
and stay in an abusive relationship."
That's not what I'm saying. I'm talking
about just the normal
human
>> thing. Sometimes you're a little short
or
>> But let me Yeah, let me push back on
that though
>> cuz I want to save longsuffering for
longsuffering.
>> Okay.
>> Right.
>> I want to So this is
>> so just show love. I feel like you're
showing love by not responding.
>> So
>> in the way that you want to respond.
Something Dr. White says, don't say the
first thing, second, third, fourth,
fifth, sixth, seventh, like don't say
any of those things like
>> Yeah. So I think show love.
>> Yeah. I think that is a that is e almost
more of a
Okay, here. I think what you're looking
for maybe practicing love like
just because,
>> right,
>> to someone.
>> So, it's a spouse, a child. I mean, I
think as parents, we do that all the
time. Like, we're just like, but
>> showing love to someone where you don't
have to like you're just practicing just
show showing love.
>> So,
>> just because.
>> So, I I'm I just thought of something. I
just thought of something that is not in
the book. There's definitely not in this
chapter that I now wish, man, that would
have been nice to put in the book. But
in in fighting, you have offensive moves
and you have defensive moves, right?
>> So, is that true?
>> I'm just kind of talking off the top of
my head now.
>> Is this is the same thing true with
these nine fruit of the spirit?
>> Right.
>> Yeah. Is there is there offensive love
and defensive love?
>> If there is there offensive joy and
defensive joy,
>> right? Like what can I do? So for
example, me going out and doing
something
um kind to someone who didn't ask for
it. That would be an offensive, right?
>> How can I practice offensive love? And
then there's defensive love where
someone does something to you and you
can respond and be mean, but hey, you
know what? I'm gonna I'm gonna respond
in a more loving way.
>> So,
>> like when we go and feed the homeless,
>> that would be offensive.
>> Offensive love. And and I love offensive
love and defensive too, but offensive
love is so beautiful because it blesses
the person and you you like feel amazing
that you made their day so good and you
know you didn't have to do that.
>> Yep.
>> It feels really really good.
>> It's like a
>> and I I think it's almost as if if we
because you you don't Okay, you don't
know. It's not up to you
to
you don't determine when you practice
when you're put in a defensive position.
>> You see what I'm saying?
>> So, you really don't have any control
>> over reactive righteousness, Nicole,
>> versus proactive righteousness. I like
that.
>> Yeah.
>> So, proactive righteousness I have
control over. I can practice that every
>> day,
>> but I don't know when somebody's going
to come at me sideways. I don't know
when someone's going to say something to
me that is offensive. I don't know when
someone's going to do something or put
me in a situation.
>> So, I may not be able to practice
defensive
righteousness
>> as often as I'm able to practice
practice offensive righteousness.
>> And many of us don't practice offensive
righteousness at all. So, when the
defense comes up, we're just there's no
defense at all.
>> We're just like walking targets,
>> right?
>> Yeah. I think practicing offensive. So
it's in our power
>> makes it easier
>> to do the defense defensive. Yeah. Yeah.
>> It just
>> when it arises, you know, how often are
you tempted to be impatient? You may not
You may not have been tempted to be
impatient yesterday or last week or last
month and it may just come out the blue
when you least expect it. But if I can
say it this way, the more offensive
practice you have Mhm.
>> the better prepared you will be
defensively when it comes to defensive
righteousness.
>> So there's offensive righteousness,
there's defensive righteousness or
proactive righteousness and then
reactive righteousness. We cannot
control defensive righteousness when it
happens. We cannot control
uh reactive righteousness when it
happens. In other words, we don't
control when someone else is going to is
going to flip out, is going to put you
in a situation. But you can control
proactive righteousness. So, how do I
then practice proactive love? And I
still got the question in the chat. So,
um
you go,
>> you know, pastor, um
>> one second, Terry, there's the this is
for our our broadcast team. There there
are people in the chat saying that we
sound like super low. Um and others are
saying no, it's just fine. So, I'm just
I'm not exactly sure. um if there's
anything that we need to do or if you
all need to just turn your sound up. Um
but
our guests are hearing us and I think
yeah I'm not sure what the issue might
be. So, just so that we you all know
that we're
>> we see some of your comments saying,
"Hey, we can't hear."
>> um
um so yeah, Terry and then
>> Yeah, go ahead, Terry.
>> Kazia, I want to see is her mic.
>> Can we Kazia, could you say something so
we can see if we can hear you because I
think somebody said you like they
thought you had something to say but
your mic wasn't um maybe there was some
audio issue. But Terry, go ahead because
you're going to share something.
>> Yeah. Um, I am really loving this idea
of practicing and practicing in the
small practical things and some of our
our watchers put it in the chat and in
in our world. I found for me it really
helps a lot, right? Um, uh, just a smile
in a in a frowning world or in traffic,
uh, I will intentionally just make sure
I let people in because everybody's in a
hurry and they want to get on those
horns, right? and they and and so I'll
just let people in or I'll let people
go. Um I'll open the door for people. Um
I'll let people pass in front of me. Um
>> um maybe at work sometimes the young
guys get really crazy with all the
music. Um and I'll just go and grab
water for everybody and take it around
the entire shop and give everybody water
or um one um in the neighborhood some
it's it's just in a lot of small things.
And I found that like Michaela said, uh
Melinda said, you know, rather than in
trying to produce fruit, I will just I
want to be Jesus. And so I make myself
available to him in these small things
and more and more. He says, "Okay, T, if
you're going to be faithful in the small
things, then I'll give you more and I'll
show you other ways you can do it in
bigger ways you can do it." And so I I
actually started doing that even to the
place of where there may be uh people
don't like to pick up behind their dogs
sometimes. And uh and so do that for
them.
>> They don't do that.
>> They they don't they don't. And
>> do you say that your love and kind you
go and pick up their dog's mess?
>> Yes, ma'am. Wow.
>> And and you know it's that is
>> it's a it's these are the little
practices. See sometimes we're looking
for that big
>> you practicing. You practicing.
>> Well, we're looking for those big old
things, but the Lord says you start with
these little things. When that big one
comes, you've already built up the love
muscle in the spirit. So, you can do it.
>> This is wax on, wax off.
>> Brush up,
>> brush down,
>> uh, wash on, wash off. That's what that
is.
>> When we're looking for these,
>> and for those of you who have no idea
what I got,
>> I know the girls look like, what is he?
What is he?
>> They're like, what?
>> This is um,
>> this is this was our generation.
>> Karate Kid,
>> Karate Kid, Mr. Miyagi
uh teaching Ralph Machio how to fight.
He didn't like I want to learn how to
fight. And instead he gave him a
paintbrush and told him brush up, brush
down, gave him a you know uh told him to
wax the car, wax on, wax off and didn't
know that the whole time he was being
trained
>> on how to fight
>> on how to fight. He just thought my
teacher has me painting. He's like, "I
want to learn how to fight. Help me do
this." He was mad and washing cars,
drying cars off. And he was just
>> mad and didn't know he was being trained
the whole time. A lot of times we're
looking for the big thing,
>> right?
>> To learn how to demonstrate love when
when God is saying, "Listen,
>> I I want you to wax on." In Car's in
Terry's case, pick up
>> Terry. I like I'm telling you that that
you I'm glad you gave that example
because I don't even have a dog and I'm
like man
that would I would be very tempted to
not be happy. So that's a good practice
in love like to pick up somebody else's
stuff.
Yes, it's a great practice.
>> Um can I hear something? Y since you
guys are my mic was probably not
agreeing but I hope it's working now.
>> Yes, we hear you.
Okay. Um maybe what I can kind of say on
the spirit of love is um just based on
>> Oh man. Oh,
>> I wanted to hear what she had to say.
When we get her back, uh she'll
definitely be able Oh, you're there. Is
she there? Is she back?
>> I'm back. Sorry.
>> Okay.
>> Bad internet.
Um, I have a younger sister and
sometimes it's very hard to have the
spirit.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, well, for those of you who don't
know that she's actually in Tanzania, so
wherever she is Oh, man. doesn't have.
We're so blessed to have her and be a
part of our uh to be a part of our youth
team and we're just so thankful and we
just do look forward to hearing what she
has to say, but wherever she is is
having some internet issues. So, um does
anyone else want to pick up with that
thought of how to practice love, the
fruit of love?
Michaela, are you gonna say something or
because otherwise I would Go ahead.
>> Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Okay. Yeah, go ahead. So, um
I don't know, maybe this isn't like a
practical thing, but to me the verse we
love because he first loved us
>> has a directly practical application
because I feel like if you're if you've
realized that Christ has freed you from
your guilt, he's freed you from your
sin, he's freed you from from all these
things, then you're going to just be
astonished by this love and you're going
to be like, "Wow, oh my goodness, I
can't even fathom that and you're just
going to be so thankful and
you're going to transfer that
thankfulness and that gratitude to other
areas in your life. So when someone
comes at you sideways,
um it's gonna be easier to
um work with them because you're like,
"Hey, I've been a total brat to the Lord
myself." And you know,
>> Amen.
>> who's who said it so nicely. Some one of
the martyrs was like, you know, Jesus
died and bled on a cross for me. I can
go to the fire for him or something like
that. And I just think that's the right
attitude when it comes to love. It's
because he first loved us.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen. No, that was beautiful.
>> Thank you.
>> Amen.
>> Let me I'm going to add to add to that
thought. You know, when
when we go to the cross
and we see
what the magnitude of what Jesus did for
us,
it makes everything else small.
>> Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. And I think the
problem that a lot of us have is that we
amplify so much.
>> Yes.
>> This person said this to me and it's the
end of the world.
>> Right. Right?
>> And we magnify
we magnify these issues to where we
produce enemies because
um
because it's
in our own minds the wrongest thing that
ever happened in the world. Mhm.
>> When we go to the cross and we see
>> how much Jesus did for us, how much he
accomplished for us, how much he loved
us,
>> um
>> I think we learn to minimize,
we learn to to we get the ability to
shrink down the things that the devil
was blowing up in our minds.
>> Yeah.
And I think when we can shrink things
down to a manage manageable size,
>> it becomes easier to overcome that
thing,
>> right? It becomes easier not to hold
grudges.
>> Exactly.
>> You know, I know for me when someone if
someone has done something wrong against
me and and maybe this is a good thing, I
don't know. Maybe I don't know. But if
someone asks me for forgiveness,
I I'm all my almost default default
position is what are you talking about?
>> Yeah, he does that.
>> Yeah. Forgiveness for what? And they'll
laugh.
>> Amen.
>> You know, and I'm just
>> forgiveness. And this is like, you know,
people who will do things like, "Pastor,
I hated you for 10 years. I hated
everything you said and blah blah blah
blah. Will you forgive me?"
And I'll be like, "Forgive you for
what?"
>> And they'll be like, "No, pastor.
Really?" And I'm like, "Forgive you for
what?" I And I don't know what they're
talking about, but it's just my way of
saying, "Listen, just
>> it's gone.
>> It's is done.
>> You don't need to gravel. You don't need
to No, what are you talking about?
>> You don't need to gravel, but asking for
forgiveness is what God has called us to
do. So, I think they're doing the right
thing."
>> This is why I said I don't know if you
know it's it's wrong on my part or not
to be like, "What are you talking
about?" But it's I guess it's my you
know it's it's my because I I I hate
seeing people
>> I know
>> even in the least have to gravel for
anything.
>> Amen.
>> But the Lord calls for it.
>> But again, I think if we learn to we're
able to learn to just minimize,
you know, hey, let me let me shrink this
down in my mind and that way I can
better fight it. I can better deal with
it. How can we how can we
>> you can shrink it down in your mind, but
if you know you've harmed somebody and
you hurt somebody,
>> Yeah.
>> the right is to go and apologize. And
it's so powerful for because even though
you say like, "Oh, what did you do?"
It's still because we've walked away
from situations and we've seen God bring
things full circle
>> this summer was that happened hugely
>> and people that
>> were very mean
>> came
individually but almost as a group and I
don't know if the Holy Spirit just spoke
to each one like or if they
>> prayed about it and came together either
way and apologized and it was so huge.
It was so healing. So, it's healing for
the person, but it's healing for you.
It's healing for you, too. You're going
to feel so much better to
>> Amen.
>> get that off of your chest and that
person. Extend the for the accept that,
you know, apology and you can move
forward. It's the best feeling.
>> And it happens so often,
>> especially in your marriages and with
your children.
>> Yeah.
>> Say sorry.
>> Okay. Y
>> because it's so big, especially with
your kids, man.
>> Yeah,
>> with your husband, too. With your wife,
it's huge.
>> It's huge. This is not a marriage thing,
but we could do a little marriage
seminar here.
>> I'm sure many would appreciate it. Many
would appreciate it. Yeah,
>> our um
>> I'm going to give you guys closing
remarks because our
producer directors have said we've gone
over our time, which is true, but
they're keeping us to a time schedule,
which is good. So, I'm going to let you
guys do your closing remarks because we
can continue this next week.
>> Okay. I was just going to say having the
spirit of love is very important. Um I
want to share a quote from Ellen White
from the book Prayer Chapter 5. Um,
paragraph 50, it says, "When about to
speak passionately, close your mouth. Do
not utter a word, pray before you speak,
and heavenly angels will come to your
assistance."
>> And having the spirit of love, spirit of
love, you must have you must you must
just be able to be able to do that.
>> Amen.
>> Yeah, that's what I was gonna say.
>> Amen. Beautiful. So glad that you we
were able to get you back and you were
able to say that. Praise God. Praise
God.
>> Amen.
>> Does anyone else have any closing
remarks that you'd like to share on on
what we've discussed today
and it's okay not trying to put anybody
on the spot. It's fine. It's fine. Uh
because we will be right back here next
week hopefully. I mean, we might get
might get Bri, might get Lami. We'll
see. Continue to pray for Bri. She's
doing well, but she was in a car
accident with and her three of her kids
were there. But God is good and um
they're okay. But I know that was
traumatizing for the little kids. But
>> we're just so thankful for our our guest
and everything that was shared. Praise
God for our new official member. Amen.
And we are looking forward to um going
into the divine worship. So please, the
link was shared. You might have to go
way up in the chat, but the link was
shared. Um but if you're not on Mighty
Networks uh please get on Mighty
Networks and the link was also shared in
the chat where you can get access to the
chapters uh one two three and four and
so that you could be studying with us.
So we want you guys reading it
throughout the week. Bring your insight
put it in the chat. It's it it's amazing
the this book is very life-changing. So
really encouraging everyone to to get
your own copies.
>> Yeah. And let me say this. I see a
question from chess with Lu Mafua. I
don't know if said that last name right.
And the question was like how do you how
do you deal with someone who's you know
borrowed money from you and you know has
never paid it back. You know how do you
respond to something to a situation like
that? And I think that is those are some
of the very practical things. That's a
defensive righteousness.
>> Yeah.
>> Right there that you have to think think
of it like this.
>> That's hard. How many how much do we owe
Jesus
>> that we have not
given to him?
>> Right? And you know, you can't control
whether another person is going to ever
do right by you.
>> So given that they may do right, but
given that they're not, how do you
maintain under that in that defensive
posture? How do you maintain your
righteousness in that defensive posture?
You know, dealing with something that is
requiring you to to show love
regardless,
>> to show mercy regardless, to show
kindness regardless.
>> You can Yeah. I mean, if you've if
you've appro this this is this is okay.
Well, if you've approached the person
and and just
kindly reminded them, be like, "Hey, do
you have any plans to, you know, pay
that money back or, you know, is your
situation any better now?" or you know
just kindly remind them and then they
don't then I would say
>> you need to probably forgive them not
probably you need to forgive them
because that is you know wrong to not
pay you back
>> and then God calls us to be wise I
wouldn't let the person borrow again
because they're not pay they didn't pay
back but I you definitely I would try to
be kind a kind reminder if that doesn't
work then you have you have to forgive
them and you don't really have any other
choice you're not going to take
>> you don't want to take that uh to the
grave and you can't take it to heaven So
>> yeah,
>> forgive different ways to work that
situation out
>> and definitely pray.
>> And you know what? You might be called
>> to have them borrow again.
>> But right,
>> you're not your found.
They ask for your cloak.
You give them You never know what the
Lord is going to call you to do and how
he's trying to,
>> you know, how he's bringing you up to a
wax on, wax off moment.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. A brush on, brush up, wash on,
brush up, brush down, wash on, wash off
moment. You just never know. So,
learning how to stay in tune with the
spirit and and move according to the
flow of the spirit. This is one of the
reasons why we want to try to practice
offensive righteousness
as much as possible.
>> Possible. Yeah, you're right. That's a
hard one. That's a hard one for me.
Yeah,
>> he knows.
>> But, you know, it's it's amazing,
pastor.
It's amazing you guys. Uh, some people
are just so strong in one area and kind
of not so strong in the other area. And
so, you know, you might be over here
thinking, "Okay, I'll pick up the dog
poop." That's what happens. And then
somebody don't give you a bread. You be
like, "Wait,
>> I can pick up dog poop, but you asking
me for more money and you ain't paying
me back. I'm not a bank.
>> Whoa, where my money at?"
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. But this
really helps us to look at ourselves and
look at Yeah. Look at everything. This
is we're in training.
>> Yeah,
>> we're in training. Righteousness by
faith.
>> Yeah.
>> God has the faith. He'll train us.
>> This been has been amazing, guys. Thank
you again. We look forward to uh doing
this again next week uh for as many that
came with us. But we'll be here.
Hopefully the majority of you guys will
be here or all or more. And please uh
our viewing audience go to mighty
networks download the chapters and so
that you can like be sharing in the chat
with us. Let's do this together.
>> Yeah. And uh the sermon coming up today,
left Jesus, right Jesus.
Um you will not want to miss this.
>> Yes.
>> Um there's another half to that title
that I just have not wanted to say but
will say at some point in my sermon. So
>> okay. uh left Jesus, right? Jesus.
Please, please, please share the link.
Let people know that they need to tune
in to watch this message because we're
going to we're going to talk about some
very, very timely,
crucial,
and critical things for
our church family.
>> Amen. And I want to say happy
anniversary to Ardent and her husband.
They're celebrating their anniversary
today and they're viewing and they've
been blessed. So, praise God on your
anniversary. Yeah.
>> Yes. It's always a blessing to have many
years. Amen. Of marriage. So, praise
God. Please share this link on your
social media. Share it now because the
divine worship service is going to
happen here very shortly. And you want
to invite all of your friends and family
on your social media or just copy this
link and send it in a text to uh those
that you know that you want them to to
be able to be blessed as well. So this
is the time to do it. Share, share,
share.
>> All right, we'll see you at Divine
Service. And I'll say this and subscribe
to uh Living Mana as a YouTube page if
you have not already done so. This is
also the time to do that.
>> Amen.
>> Okay. So pray.
>> All right. Heavenly Father, thank you
for giving us an opportunity, Lord, to
to get uh to study and to talk and to
share about this art of war, the
Christian art of war. Lord, um L Lord,
teach us how to fight um
how to fight in the spirit, not only
offensively, Lord, but also defensively.
>> Amen.
>> Lord, teach us what offensive
righteousness looks like.
>> And um and Lord, help us to practice it
daily
>> as it is under our control. Lord, help
us to produce that fruit by staying
connected to the tree, connected to the
vine, connected to the cross. And Lord,
may we bear fruit because of our
connection in you and not offer you the
dead fruits of our own works. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
[Music]
Prepare
[Applause]
to stay here for 100 more. If that's
what it takes to protect mom and kill
and if that's not enough, we'll stay
here for 100 more. And if that's not
enough, we'll stay here for 100 more.
I'm not Hawaiian by blood, but I'm
Hawaiian by heart. My grandmother was
born on Maui, daughter of a plantation
worker. I was born and raised in Wua in
Nanakuli on Aahu. This is the only home
I know, and I'm blessed to be Kei Oka, a
child of this land. My wife and I were
in Russia when we saw the videos of the
stand here on Mount Aaya. We're speaking
each night to over a thousand Russian
young people at a spiritual youth
congress under the theme striving for
the highest. And though we were there on
the other side of this world, our hearts
and our prayers were here with the
people on this mountain. When we flew
back home, we came immediately here to
listen, to learn, to absorb, and to
stand. The kapuna tell us ka canu which
means aim for the highest and strive for
the summit. And that's what we've done
here today. You see, Mount Aaya is the
highest mountain in the world from the
ocean floor. It is the peak and the
pinnacle of Havaii. We stand on this
mountain today in Kapu Aloha, holding
ourselves up to the highest standards of
aloha at Pono. And as we have physically
ascended the mounta, we're called to
rise mentally and spiritually as well.
But today, our hearts are heavy because
we see our aa trampled upon by greed and
lust and vanity. Our hearts are sore
because we've seen the aloha spirit
commercialized for profit by those who
know not what it is. But though our
hearts are heavy, we like this ma must
rise above it.
When the fierce and strong hurricane
clashes with the ma, it remains on paha
steadfast. The ma overcomes the storm.
And in the same way as a people, we face
a fierce storm today. a storm of
oppression that has brought disease, a
drug epidemic, homelessness, pollution,
and brokenness in our beloved land. And
as we've seen and experienced oppression
and injustice, our human nature wants to
respond in the same way, to respond in
anger and vengeance and even war. But
today, a coup is calling us to kalya, to
strive for the summit, to go higher in
our thinking and our actions and our
reactions. And this, my friends, is the
call of Kaku aloha.
But please consider with me that before
we can go as high as this mountain, we
must first go deep like the ocean. The
mountain is the tallest in the world
because it finds its foundation deep on
the ocean floor. And this is a life
lesson for us. In order for us to reach
to the highest heavens, we must first go
to the deepest ocean. You can only go
high as you first go deep. You see,
every tree has branches and it's the
branches that hold the fruit of the
tree. But the branches are only as
strong as the roots. In order to have
sweet fruits, you first must have
healthy roots. You see, what the aa is
teaching us is that in order for us to
only to stand tall and steadfast, we
must first go deep to the roots. My
generation are the branches and the
fruit of our kuna. We are the answer to
their pulle, their prayers, but they are
our roots. We must remember those who
came before us and never forget the
lessons of our elders and our history.
But please consider with me that Aku is
calling us to go even deeper than that.
For you can only go as high as you first
go deep. So the deeper you go, the
higher you will go as well. So in order
to Kalia Ekan to reach for the summit of
this mountaintop experience, we must go
far deeper than the land that our feet
walks upon. And we must reach back even
further before our kapuna and before
their kapuna. We must go back to the
beginning of time to find the truest and
the purest form of capuhoha. And where
is that you ask?
In the beginning, Akua created the
heavens and the earth. And a kua said,
"Let there be light." And there was
light. You see friends, before our kuna
and even before our aa there was only a
kua. The Bible says that Akua made the
aina first, then he made mankind after.
Then he gave the aa to the first kanaka
ma, the original man. The Bible says
that Akua gave the aina to us to have
dominion over. The Bible is clear that
the kanaka are the guardians of this
land. But the land can only be
perpetuated in righteousness. And
tragically, there have been many who
have misunderstood and misinterpreted
this biblical truth. Some missionaries
of the past and clergy of the present
have used this to justify the taking,
the exploiting and the destroying of the
but in Genesis chapter 2 A tells us how
we're to have dominion over the Aina. It
says that we're to dress it and to keep
it. In other words, we're to be stewards
of the land. Servants of Aku called to
malama, the aa. This is the true origin
of aloha.
We exercise dominion over the a not by
exploitation but by aloha. This is what
I call servant leadership. We lead and
we rule. We dominate and we conquer not
by the power of force but by our service
and our aloha to the land and our
service and aloha to one another. by
continuing to do what we're doing here
today in Capu aloha to hold ourselves up
to the highest standards of pono and
aloha to respond to those who desecrate
our aa with the highest level of
nonviolent resistance respect compassion
empathy patience strength and love to
show the whole world that the mana of
aloha conquers all so I call upon you
today my beloved lahi in the name of a
to remain on pa in the mana of kapu
aloha
One last thing I'm compelled to share
with you is this. There is another
mountain that is even higher than this
one. A mountain that is demonstrated
most clearly to us. The mana of Capo
Aloha. It is a mountain that our Capuna
and many of our beloved kings and queens
of Havi look toward for strength to
endure the storms they faced. It is the
mountain called Calvary. For it is there
that Akuma sent his beloved son Yesu to
die in the cross for each one of us. And
on that sacred mountain by the mana of
Capu aloha Yesu conquered all the forces
of oppression, injustice, hatred and
violence. He laid down his life in order
to free us from the oppression of sin.
He laid down his life to provide for us
here today the mana to remain onipa in
capu aloha. The power to remain
steadfast in love. to love those who
would disrespect us, to pull those who
would oppress us, to bless those who
would harm us, to resist those who would
trample upon us, to forgive those who
would take advantage of us.
So let us go up to the mountain, not
only physically, but mentally and
spiritually. Let us reach back even
further and go even deeper so that we
can rise even higher. Let us kala to
strive for the summit. I appeal to you
my beloved lahi and all of those who
face difficulties and oppression around
the world. In the name of Akua to focus
and look even higher than the aa that we
can see with our physical eye with the
eye of faith. Let us look beyond the
furthest star and the most distant
galaxy that any man-made telescope can
penetrate. Let us look to the return of
a Yesu in the clouds of heaven. Soon he
will return to take us to our heavenly
aua, a land that no one will be able to
take from us. Let us look up towards
this mountain here today. But let us
also look even higher to the mountain of
Calvary where we obtain the mana of Capu
aloha. And then let us look again even
higher yet to our heavenly Holly, our
heavenly Au pua of which our beloved
Havi is a reflection of. For there in
that beautiful land, we will never be
oppressed again. Injustice will end.
Sickness will be no more. Death itself
will die. Our tears will dry up.
Laughter will never cease and joy will
never dim. Our capuna will never age and
our kei will never die. The sky will
never darken and the flowers will never
fade. Our waters will always be clean
and our land will always be beautiful
and our ma will continue to stand.
Aloha. Aloha kakua. Aloha kako. I'll see
you in that heavenly ma.
Hello.
[Music]
I'm alle. We are
now
[Music]
Only power
upon
[Music]
Heat. Hey, Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat up
here.
[Music]
Heat up here.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
We're so happy that you decided to
continue to worship with us. If you are
joining us for the first time today,
please put in the chat where you are
viewing from. We'd like to say a special
welcome to you. Oh, it's always fun
every single week to see all the
different areas where you guys are
viewing from. And if this is your first
time, please put a one in the chat. I
actually saw somebody um during this
time put um somebody put in the chat,
hey newcomers, put a one in the chat.
You guys, you said it before I said it.
That's great. I love you taking that
initiative to do that. So, we want to
know uh we want to say a special welcome
to you. We want to know where you guys
are viewing from. So, please put all of
that in the chat. Uh during our first uh
service during Sabbath school, we saw
somebody was in China and I think that
was the first time somebody was watching
um us that was in China. Uh we found out
that they're actually from the UK, but
they were currently in China and they
were watching Living Mana. Um so that
was cool. We thought that was really
cool. I want to say happy Sabbath and
welcome to Mooney in Toronto, Canada.
Welcome to Living Mana Church. Barbara
from Mississippi, welcome uh to Living
Mana Church. So good to see you here
worshiping with us today. And I know
that there are uh many more out there.
So please put in the chat if you're just
joining us. If you didn't put it in the
chat the first time, let us know that
you are watching so we can say uh
welcome to you. We have Ashley from
Dylan, South Carolina. Welcome to Living
Mana Church. We have MH from St. Croy,
um, Virgin Islands visiting. Welcome.
Also, uh, Keats Island in Canada. Happy
Sabbath and welcome. Alfonso from
Massachusetts, good to see you here. Uh,
Jonelle from Medford, Oregon, welcome to
Living Mana Church. Regina from
Brooklyn, New York, good to see you
here. Always good to see you. Ayana from
uh, Trinidad and Tobago.
like to welcome Sharon uh from Maryland
and Nicole from Australia. Wonderful.
Nicole, what part of Australia is it?
Sydney area, the Perth side. We've never
I've never been to Perth, so I'm always
I I still want to go there. So, I don't
know what side, but always good to see
you, Crystal Cox. Like I say all the
time, still praying for you and wishing
you and your family the best. Um, okay,
it's going up fast. I got Okay, it's
going up really fast. I got to go here.
Britney from Arizona. Good to see you
here uh as well. Welcome, welcome,
welcome. Good to see all of you guys
from many different areas. We have
Andre, another one from Toronto, Canada.
Good to see you here. Welcome to Living
Mana Church. Um, and I'm There's
Colombia, Columbia, British Columbia,
Canada. I missed I missed the name. It's
going up fast here and it's going fast
there. So, all right. Nicole from
Melbourne. Yes, we've been to Melbourne.
We have good friends there. We visited a
church um I my husband did a week of
prayer I don't know back in 2018
I think that was and we have some really
really good friends in Melbourne. So
that's great. Christopher from London,
welcome to Living Mana Church. I could
go on and on and on and on. Uh Karen
from Jamaica, good to see you here.
Welcome to Living Mana Church. We don't
have any ones but that's okay. We have
all of you are coming back. you must
have enjoyed and were blessed by the
times that you have come here before and
so you're back. So, praise God. Still,
if you're here for the first time,
please put a one in the chat. Um, and
our membership and our viewing audience
will say a very special welcome to you.
Just want to let you guys remind you how
you can stay connected. If you have not
as of yet signed up to get text alerts,
you need to do that. That is how you
stay connected with Living Matter
Church. It reminds you of all of our Oh,
as I'm saying this, we have Casey. She's
new. Welcome, Casey. So good to have you
here at Living Mana Church. Please
listen to all these announcements
because it's going to tell you a lot
about our church. So, it's perfect
timing for you to have put a one. But
please welcome Casey, everyone, to
Living Mana Church. And Jonell, welcome
both of you. So glad that you're here
with us today. So to stay connected to
Living Man Church, you need to sign up
for text uh messages so that uh you will
uh be reminded when we're going live,
the programmings that are coming on,
different things all throughout the week
that just keep you connected to Living
Manage Church. That's if you are here in
North America, you can get these text
alerts. If you're international, I'll
tell you in just a moment on how you can
stay connected. But just going back to
that last screen that you were at, um,
you want to text LOC, text LOC to the,
uh, 855 number there. You can also scan
the QR code and that will automatically
sign you up to get those text
notifications. So, if this is your first
time and you like what you see and you
want to know more about Living Manage
Church, you definitely are going to want
to sign up. And if this is not your
first time, you've been here before, but
you still haven't signed up and you're
in North America, you need to sign up so
you can stay connected to Living Manage
Church and know what's going on. If you
are international, which is a big piece
of our church viewership and membership
is international because we are an
international church, that text alert
will not work for you. But the way that
you can stay connected is by downloading
Mighty Network. And Mighty Networks is
going to be in the chat. So you'll be
able to just click that link and be able
to sign up for Mighty Networks. And
Mighty Networks is actually our virtual
home. That is where so many things
happen. Like if you were watching
Sabbath school, the um you the book the
chapters for each lesson that we're
doing is on Mighty Networks. Um so many
you can get so much community,
find so much community on Mighty
Networks because that is where all of
our small groups are. You'll get to
learn about all the different small
groups we have going on, the leadership.
You'll be able to talk to them, get to
know people better um here at Living
Mana Church and different announcements.
Mighty Networks is the place to be. No
matter if you are international or live
here in North America, everyone that
wants to be a part of Living Man Church,
to stay connected to to um just know
more about what's going on, you need to
sign up for Mighty Networks, but you can
also sign up for the text alerts, which
is great. They just come to your phone
um and they just remind you of all of
the things that are going on here at
Alamoc Church. Also always want to
remind you guys that if you have kids,
we have children's programming and it's
LMOC Kids and we have great uh leaders
that are helping lead out with Alamosci
kids and teaching um our children the
deep things of God's word, but having a
lot of fun while they're doing it. And
so, um, it's always just a blessing to
hear from the children that go to LMOC
kids and even the parents and the
leadership just, uh, what a blessing it
is to have, uh, this programming and to
to make it available. So, if you have
children and that you want to sign up
for Loc, you can do that by sending an
email to LMC kids at living.urch church
or you can te k text kids to that 855
number and you will be able to sign your
kids up. Also want to remind you guys
that pastor Myers does have virtual
office hours. So um he is your pastor
and if you need to talk to him then you
need to send an email to patrice
livingmana.live live and um she will be
able to help you set that up um for a
time that works best for you and for
Pastor Myers. So, if if that's what
you're needing, definitely send that
email. Also, just want to remind you
guys that if you would like to become a
member of Living Mana Church, you can do
so in three ways. There's three ways
that you can become a member. You can if
you are already a member of the 7th Day
Adventist Church, you can transfer your
membership. Um, and you will use that
email patrice living.live. If you are a
Christian, but you're learning things in
the Bible, uh, new things in the Bible
that the 7th Day Adventist Church
teaches, and you want to become a member
of the Seventh Day Adventist Church, but
you've already been baptized, don't feel
like you need to be rebaptized, you can
come in by through a profession of
faith. Um, and if that is your desire,
you can still email Patrice at
living.live.
And the last way that you can become a
member is you can get baptized. Um, and
you can become a member that way. And
Pastor Myers will do the baptism. Matter
of fact, we have a baptism coming up on
November 15th. That was 15th. That was
just confirmed for sure uh this week.
And so, we have a baptism coming up. So,
we're definitely looking forward uh to
that. Also, just wanted to remind you
guys um you're not going to see a
graphic for this, but I just want to
remind you guys that Mental Health
Mondays is coming up this week. Dr.
White and myself, we are gonna we'll be
back. Uh we already had our first uh
program for season 4 and this it will be
our second program for season 4. So, you
don't want to miss it. And if you sign
up to get the text alerts, you will be
reminded I think about 20 minutes before
we go live just in case you forget. And
we are going to uh by God's grace have
great mental health um a great mental
health topic for you. Uh things that are
practical, things that um that many
people are going through and hopefully
will be a blessing to you. So definitely
tune in to Mental Health Mondays at 700
p.m. Central time. And again, you will
get a text alert and if you're on Mighty
Networks, you will get information about
that as well. So we enjoy doing that pro
that program, Dr. White and myself. So
I'm praying that you enjoy that as well.
So yes, want to just remind you guys
that we have the power line. The power
line is amazing. It's right after we
have uh Power Wednesdays. Uh Power
Wednesdays is our prayer meeting where
our prayer team leads out in that and
amazing testimonies are shared there.
You're putting your prayer request in
there. All of that stuff. There's music,
there's fellowship, it's all there in
power Wednesday. And the power line is
something that you can use as an
evangelistic tool for the Lord. um you
can come and bring your prayer request
to the power line of course but you
could also tell other people about it so
that they could other people who are not
involved and they're not you know in our
church just anybody somebody you meet on
the street your co-orker family member
they say hey I need prayer for this
definitely pray for them right there but
also tell them hey my church will pray
for you and invite them to tune in 8 to
have them tune in at 8:00 p.m. central
time, put their prayer request in the
chat and it will be prayed over live
right uh during that time. This is not
this happens right then. All they do on
the power line is pray. That's it. They
pray. So, it's a great way to um
introduce um your friends and family
members to Living Mana Church and to God
and through prayer. It's a great it's a
great ministry. So, we're very excited
about that. want to remind you guys uh
that Hangouts um you want to mark your
calendar because Hangouts um is every
other Sunday. So, um it was uh this last
week, but the next one will be October
5th at 6:30 p.m. And I have to tell you,
I've been able I didn't get to attend
this last one, but I've attended two of
them and they've been the first two and
they've been amazing. I've gotten to
know so many of you in a deeper way and
just in a fun way. So, you definitely
want to do that. Um but again, hangouts
will take place every other Sunday
evening. Um our hangouts hosts are
inviting you into their virtual living
rooms and will guide you through ice
breakers, meaningful dialogue, uh share
hobbies and interests and help all of us
to get to know each other better. Uh we
we all start out together in the in the
main Zoom meeting. Um from there we do
the they will take you into a breakout
smaller group room of 10 or less. So, if
you have any social anxiety, you don't
have to worry about it uh as much
because it's not going to be this huge
group that you end up being with, but
it's going to be 10 or less people. Um,
and they are inviting you. You can you
can scan the QR code. You can also text
Hangouts to the 855 number to get more
information and to also get on uh the
list so you can u be reminded of when
Hangouts is happening. But it is a lot
of fun to be able to get again to get to
know each other, build community. People
always say, "How do you build community
on an online church?" Just heard that
question yesterday. And honestly, we
have great community, great connections
with people that we really have never
met, but we feel so close to, and that's
the amazing thing. So, definitely join
LMC and the Hangout crew because they
want to bring you lots of community and
laughter and fun and happiness.
All right, men of Loc,
stay connected. Just um just a reminder
that our awesome men's ministry is
thriving and ready to connect with you
led by our brother Elco. This ministry
is all about growth, brotherhood, and
walking boldly in purpose. The new
contact email is menlivingmana.urch.
That's men living.
That's how you can stay uh connected.
You can also text men to that 855
number um so that you can sign up for
our men's ministry as well. And they
meet on Tuesdays at 7:30 p.m. Central
time. So if you are interested in that,
please send a text to the 855 number
that you see on your screen. And
remember, men, it's not hard at
living.urch.
And so that's how you can sign up to be
a part of that. Also want to remind you
guys about the healing hour.
This is a small group. Uh do you or
someone you love um live with a chronic
illness? You're not alone. Join Sister
Angela for the healing hour, a space of
encouragement, prayer, and faith
building. Every first Sunday of the
month at 12:00 p.m. Central Standard
Time, come be inspired, receive
resources, grow in faith, and seek
healing in community. This is more than
a meeting. It's a movement of hope.
Questions uh please reach out on the
mighty uh network app. Let's walk this
journey together. It's a beautiful
ministry uh the small group that sister
Angela um has created. So definitely
want to encourage you guys um if you
feel that that group would be a blessing
uh for you. Also want to remind you that
instead of on the last Sabbath of every
month, instead of going on the afterlow,
you're going to do the aftergo.
Feed others from what you have received.
Uh the last Sabbath of each month, um we
pause our our usual afterlow discussion
and step into the aftergo. A time to
live out what uh we have been fed. you
you will you have received the word,
you've been nourished in truth. Now go
out with joy and lead forth in space and
do that for somebody else. Um the verse
here is Isaiah uh 55:12. That is what
God is calling us to do. So go and be a
blessing on the last Sabbath of every
month month and participate in after go
and you can come up with whatever way
that you want to do that. If you want to
go do a kind act for somebody um or just
go be a blessing to somebody um that is
what we are encouraging you to do. Want
to also just remind you guys that we
have LMOC Global which is uh a way that
we can take the messages that you hear
on Living Mana Church and we can uh send
them out or we are sending them out in
seven seven different languages. We want
it to encourage you to continue to pray
for LMOC Global and to if you would like
to give to LMOC Global, we want to
encourage you to do that, too. But let
me give you an example of what LMOC
Global is.
The ghost writer.
cannot speak Korean. Uh so but it
because of the technology that we're
able to purchase, we have are able to
make it sound like pastor Myers is
speaking seven
We want to support LMLC
are to do that uh by uh giving to living
mana church and there are areas um on
your if you give to the the um the local
church budget that that there is how you
are able to support Alamosc Global. Um,
but just continue to keep it in prayer.
And if you can go on uh Mighty Networks,
you can see or no, I'm sorry. Go to
Alamosc Global uh YouTube page and you
will see all of the languages that we
offer there. And if that if there's any
of those languages there that you know
somebody that they speak that, then you
might want to share that with them. So
continue to keep LMLC Global in prayer.
I want to just remind you guys how you
can give to Living Mana Church. And the
virtual way to be able to um give your
tithe and offering is to go to
adventistgiving.org.
That's the virtual way you're able to
give and support Living Mana Church. Um
and so there if you just put in Living
Mana Church, then a virtual tithe
envelope will appear. And as you can see
there, you can um just give your tithe.
You can put in your local how what you
want to do to give the offering for the
local church budget. There are many
different categories there. We have the
benevolence fund and it is that fund
that we use to be able to help people
who are in need and asking for
assistance. There's so many other areas
that you will see there on the tithe
envelope. And so you can choose where
you want to give to. If this virtual
um app or website is not where you would
like to give, but you would like to mail
in your tithe and offering, you can do
that by mailing it to P Box 428
Owens Crossroads, Alabama 35763.
And you just write your checkout to
Living Mana Church. And also like to
remind people you please put a note uh
where you would like your offering uh to
go to and what you uh how much is for
offering, how much is for tithe and what
where other areas that you are wanting
to give to. And so we just always want
to say thank you and we appreciate you
following um God's leading uh on your
heart to want to give back uh to his
cause and uh we again are just so
thankful for the faithfulness um of your
presence of your prayers and your
financial gifts as well. And we again
are just so thankful. I can't say that
enough. We've been here in this coming
April will be four years. So, we're like
three and a half years in and it still
amazes me and I think it's amazing other
people too because this was definitely a
a a walk of faith probably the biggest
leap and walk of faith that I personally
ever endeavored in. Um many of you know
that my husband was excited about it and
at f at first and I was like not so
excited about it because I was like how
are we going to do an online church? How
is this going to work? I had some of the
same questions you may have if you're
just joining us now for the first time.
But God has taken all of that away. I've
seen God move and lead in this church
and it's just amazing. It's fun to be on
a faith journey with God. And that's
what this church is. It's a faith
journey with God and we just make
ourselves available and he does all the
work. He uses us but he does all the
work through us. So we praise God uh for
that. And we just want to lift up a a
praise, a worship, a praise, sorry, a
prayer to God, thanking him for all of
his goodness and mercy uh that he's
shown towards this church and to us
individually as well. So, if you would
just please bow your heads with me as we
pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, just want to
thank you for your Sabbath, Lord. Thank
you for this church. Thank you for all
the viewing audience. Father, want to
thank you for the Sabbath school this
morning and the three young people and
brother Terry for sharing with us. They
It's just such a blessing. It's I get
excited every time we go uh on the air
to talk about this topic and with these
young people. It's very exciting to see
how you're leading in their lives. And
Lord, I just want to lift up everyone
that is viewing. You know, their
individual situation. Lord, some are
have illness. They're sick or one of
their loved ones are sick. Lord, I pray
over uh them and their loved one and
whoever is in their life that they are
praying over, Lord, and it's a burden on
them. So, I just pray um or it's just a
they're just hurting for them, Lord. And
so, I just pray uh for them, Lord. I ask
that you will heal them uh and just work
your supernatural powers, Lord. Give
them peace as they are going through
this. Lord, I pray for those who are
going through financial difficulties. I
pray that you will send a financial
blessing to them, Lord. Or let somebody
forgive their debt. Um, whatever it is,
Lord, supply what they are in need of.
Lord, I always want to lift up the
marriages and the families and the
children. Lord, Satan attacks this unit
all the time because he knows when he
can destruct um the marriage or the
family or the children, he can just
impact people lives, people's lives in
such a negative way. So Lord, I just
pray that you will strengthen the
marriages, strengthen the parents as
they are raising their children and the
parents of adult children. Strengthen
them so they they can go into that next
phase of their life, just being um a
support system to their adult children,
an emotional support system, Lord, just
to be there for them as they go through
things in their own lives, Lord. And so
I just I just pray for all of these
areas that people may be dealing with,
Lord. want to lift up Pastor Meyers.
Just pray that you that your Holy Spirit
that will lead him and say the things
that you want him to say and that it
will touch our hearts in a very special
way. Lord, we ask all of these things in
Jesus precious name. Amen.
What happens in here
isn't meant to stay in here.
The hope we find in here isn't meant to
stay in here. The grace we receive in
here, the victory we proclaim in here,
the revival that begins in here isn't
meant to stay in here. Our faith is made
for movement. Our testimony is designed
to be told. This place with these
people, this is the church. And what we
do in here can change the world out
there. We celebrate freedom in here so
we can carry freedom out there. We pray
for healing in here so we can bring
healing out there. We tell the stories
of God's goodness, God's peace, and
God's love in here. So we can be the
story of God's goodness, God's peace,
and God's love out there. This is no
ordinary place. This is the body of
Christ, a chosen people with a holy
purpose brought to life by Jesus and
sent out by Jesus. We gather here. We
confess here. We worship here. Because
what we do in here can change the world
out there.
[Music]
I give myself away.
I give myself away
so you can use me. I give myself
away.
[Music]
I give myself
away so you
can use me. Here I am.
Here I stand.
Lord, my life
is in your hands.
Lord, I longing
to see
your desires
revealed in me.
I give myself away.
I give myself away
so you
can use me. I give myself away.
[Music]
I give myself away
so you can use me. Take my heart.
Take my life
as a living
sacriice.
All my dreams,
all my plans,
Lord, I place them in your hands.
I give myself away.
Oh God, I give myself away
so you
can use me. God, I give myself away.
Oh,
I give myself away
so you
can use me.
My life is not my own.
To you I belong.
I give myself I give myself to you.
My life is not my own.
To you I belong.
I give myself I give myself to you.
Father I give it to you Lord. My life is
not my own.
To you I belong.
I give myself I give myself to you.
My life is not my own.
Hey, I love
I give myself I give myself I give
myself to you.
My life is not my own.
To you I belong.
I give myself I give myself to you.
So here I am to worship.
Here I am to bow down. Here I am to say
that you're my God.
You're all together worthy,
allto together lovely.
You're all together wonderful
to me. Here
I am to worship.
Here I am to bow down. Here I am to say
that you're my God.
You're all together lovely.
All together worthy.
You're all together wonderful.
You're wonderful.
You're wonderful. You're wonderful, God.
You're beautiful.
You're beautiful. You are excellent.
You're mightyh.
You're holy.
You're worthy. You are my healer. You
are my redeemer. God, you're beautiful.
You're beautiful. And I worship. Yes, I
worship you. I lift my hands and worship
you. I bow down and worship you, Lord.
You're beautiful.
You're beautiful to me.
I'll never
know
how much it cost
to see my sins
upon that cross.
I'll never
know
how much it cost
to see my sins
upon that cross.
I'll never know
how much it cost
to see
my sins
upon that cross.
No greater love than this,
than a man would lay down his life for a
friend.
Oh,
no gater love than this.
Then a man would lay down his life for a
friend.
[Music]
God, I owe you my life.
You died that I might live.
I'm forever grateful.
[Music]
Oh,
I present my body as a living sacrifice.
Holy unto you, Lord.
[Music]
So I give myself away.
I give myself away
so you
can use me. I give myself away.
I give myself
away so you
can use me.
Use me, Jesus.
Use me, Lord.
Here I am, God. We're open
for you to pour out.
[Music]
>> Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
[Music]
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
[Music]
Amen. Greetings, saints of the most high
God. Welcome to another edition of
Living Manners Prayer and Praise Time.
So happy to be here with you guys today.
So happy to be able to worship with you.
Welcome all newcomers. I am Brother
Terry. I'm here with my lovely bride
Amra as always. And uh we're giving God
praise for another opportunity to be
able to fellowship together, to worship,
to give praise, to thank God, to just
learn and grow. And so just want to
shout out everybody today. Thank you for
joining us. Love y'all. How about you,
sweetheart? What's on your mind today?
>> You know, I just feel blessed to be
here.
>> And I'll have a little praise report to
share of my own when I read off the
praise reports. Amen. Amen. Amen. Well,
we're seeing y'all in the chat there.
Uh, hey, Sister Jody, we are definitely
going to remember to pray for El Moses
and the incredible work you are doing
there. You and Sister Michelle Grant.
Blessing. And hey, Aana, good to see
y'all all here today in the chat.
Brother Jonathan, if you're still
watching, a special shout out to you, my
beloved brother. Want to encourage you,
be encouraged. We're continuing to pray
for you, my brother.
>> Hello, Jamie.
Jamie
>> in the chat.
>> Yes, Sister Jamie from Compton, we got
your prayer request. We'll be reading
that off here in just a bit. But I
wanted to uh also say a special welcome
to Sister Takara. Sister Takara, I mean,
you're like living man family, but
official. You're a member of living
family, a living mana now. And we thank
God for you. You are unique and very
very much a blessing to us. So love you.
Um, Sister Jackie, I really wanted to
thank Sister Jackie. You know, Sister
Jackie used to always sing. We we
started the first kind of special ops
prayer team and uh, man, we used to have
hours of fellowship and prayer and song
and building one another up. For all of
you who are watching who are members of
that prayer team, that special ops team,
I'm going to be giving y'all a call. We
got we got to get back on and and iron
sharp and iron. Y'all know how we do it.
But she sang a song today, have thine
own way earlier and it really really
just touched my heart, lit my fire.
Brother Elco got on fire and I think
brother Elco was ready to preach after
he heard that song. So uh praise God for
you, sister Jackie and sister Joanne.
Last night she gave us I sing the mighty
power of God and I love her when she
sings that. That's so beautiful. So
thank you for the encouragement, folks.
>> Hello Regina.
>> Yes,
>> Lyla.
Roll call.
>> Blessing. I know it's a little roll
call. Barbara,
>> Elder Robert Plant.
>> Yes.
>> See you there. Oh y'all. Oh y'all.
Sister Patrice. Hallelujah. Everybody,
we love y'all. Uh sending out love to
y'all. Thank you for all of the prayers.
We're praying for you as well.
>> Just beautiful living man of family.
Thank y'all so much. Ardent watcher,
happy anniversary again, you guys. I
hope you're still watching right now.
Wish y'all a happy anniversary. May God
continue to bless you and keep you
closer to him and closer to each other
and uh just increase the love.
>> Hello, Ashley Owens.
>> Hey, Sister Ashley and brother John
there in Dylan, South Carolina, my old
neck of the woods. Love y'all. Pray
y'all are strong. We have got to get
together. We're trying. We're working on
it. When it happens, we gonna know it.
I'm telling you. I want to say thank you
to Michaela, Melinda, and Kazia from
Tanzania. Y'all, y'all are something
else. Thank you for joining the panel
this morning and bringing all those
beautiful insights to us. Sister Angela
was supposed to join us today for
prayer, but Sister Angela had a medical
situation. And so, we definitely want to
keep Sister Angela lifted up in our
prayer. Sister Angela sending out love
to you, my beautiful sister. And uh it
was good seeing you, you and your
daughter on those uh photos y'all did
when uh you went on her um podcast. So,
uh, thank you so much for everything
that you do here, Sister Angela. And
we're praying also for that new ministry
endeavor that that will take off and the
Lord will put his hand on that.
And I believe that's just about it,
Sister Charlotte. Ah, always got to give
you a shout out, my beloved.
>> Hi, Charlotte.
>> So, uh, hope you're watching. Hope
things are going well where you are. Uh,
we still have an appointment, Sister
Charlotte. So, Sister Charlotte's going
to come on and bless us with some of the
amazing things God's doing in and
through her life.
All right, Sister Nicole.
>> Hi, Tina. Nicole Spartan 458 said,
"Sup."
>> What's up, Dan?
>> Hello.
>> Praise the Lord. Praise the Lord. We
have another sister Nicole, too. Our our
beloved sister Nicole single.
Curtis, we love you.
>> Um, so, beloved, what's uh on the praise
report uh list today?
>> We have some pretty incredible praise
reports this week. But before I start,
just a reminder. If you have a prayer
request or you would like to submit a
praise report, please send an email to
pray living manana.urch.
If you would like to join us on the
prayer team or join a special ops prayer
team under the prayer team umbrella, we
are always looking um for those who want
to serve and pray for others. Also,
please send an email to pray
livingmana.urch.
If you are requesting a special ops team
for yourself or a loved one, please send
an email to spec ops, that's spc
ops livingmana.urch.
If you would like to join the women's
ministry on mighty networks, please send
an email to women livingmana.urch. And
finally, if you would like to join the
men's ministry, please send an email to
seven loaves. That's s e v l o a ves
living manana.urch.
>> Amen. And before you read that, I see a
couple of other special shout outs there
in the chat. Hello, Sister Jerry Harvey
Leonard from sunny San Diego. Hello,
Jerry. That's our girl, Jerry. Love you
and everything you do. I saw I saw Hello
from Hangouts.
>> Hello Hangouts.
>> Look, the Hangout crew is something
else. I was working so I missed the last
one, but I'm going tell you the first
one was something and I'm looking
forward to catching y'all on the next
one. So yes, and sister Sharon F.
Johnson, if you are watching, my sister,
praise God. I know you are excited.
Something's cooking up in your spirit
and there's a good reason for that.
God's got something for you, beloved.
Love you. and Sister Karen Johnson, my
beloved beautiful sister. Be strong.
Hold on. God has got his hands on your
life. And uh beautiful testimony. Once
again, I want to say, listen, you hold
on to your faith, my sister. You are a
blessing.
>> Amen.
>> All right. Well, I'm going to share a
little praise report from myself, but
I'm going to read it because I get
chatty and I don't want to spend too
much time on me. So, I wrote it down.
[Music]
>> I know. I know. It's miracles happen
every day, right folks?
>> That's beautiful. You said that. I
didn't have to say that. Great.
>> Okay.
I've been asking for prayer that my s my
kidney surgery date would come soon
since I'm a new patient with this
particular doctor at a continued risk of
sepsis and also because this urologist
at UC San Francisco has been on
paternity leave and is backed up. I was
supposed to have my initial consultation
with him on November 5th, but I asked if
there was anything we could do to get in
earlier.
I had a consultation with his assistant
instead and then I got a call on
Thursday that I will be having my
surgery on October 9th. Not only did
they make my surgery a priority, but
there was a cancellation and they fit me
right in. Please continue to pray
against sepsis before that time as well
as after the surgery because the risk is
high for both. and pray that this time
it will be completely successful and
that my kidney will be fully restored.
Thank you so much for all of your
prayers.
>> Amen.
>> I'm trying to keep everyone in the loop
with what's going on with me, but God
has been sustaining me and I'm so
blessed and thankful and grateful.
>> Amen. And we love sharing the prayers
reports, but I I've got to emphasize
this.
Please, living man of family, saints of
the most high God, never ever
underestimate the power of your prayers.
There are people who have only had
sepsis one time and unfortunately lost
their lives.
Miraculously,
God has allowed his beautiful daughter
to survive that thing three or four
times. And so, we know that it's only
because of the prayers of the saints
only. And so we thank God and give God
all of the praise, all the glory, all
the honor for you and for your love and
commitment. So thank you.
>> Amen.
>> Can't say enough.
>> I am so so I can feel your prayers.
>> I can feel God's presence. I can feel
your prayers.
>> Amen.
>> Uber cow. Terry and Amra for the prayers
two years ago because that prayer came
through. My eye no longer needs surgery.
>> I was going to read that later but she
caught it. Listen. Praise God, somebody.
Come on now. Wow. What a praise report.
It just popped up on the screen. I saw
it. It did. Thank God.
>> Thank God.
>> All right. Art tell Peters.
God and the Holy Spirit have been
working on our faith to answer my
request for help and giving results with
Nathaniel, my Bible worker friend, in
his life, not being defined by his
unhoused status. Yeah,
>> with the Bible readings identifying our
steps and direction through the weeks,
there was affirmation in all ways,
including employment, to be able to
sustain, although minimally one's
efforts. I knew that faith without works
is the truth. I just did not know how
much works. I am thanking God for the
opportunity to serve in the name of his
son Jesus. Amen.
>> Praise God, brother.
>> Praise God. And we will continue to pray
for Nathaniel. That is exciting to hear
that things are going well for him.
Olivia Torres, it's been quite a journey
for my daughter Razelle. She finally got
approved to lease a studio apartment
with one of her co-workers who offered
to cosign. God sent. I believe on that.
Amen.
>> She's getting ready to move into her new
place in a few days. The other answered
prayer. She will be coming the first
week of November to attend the wedding
of a childhood friend. I haven't seen
her for two and a half years. God
willing, my son Oliver and her will be
here so I can spend a little time with
them both. That is comforting to know
and to look forward to. Thank you all
for interceding in prayer as a whole for
me and my children and for continuing on
doing so. I love you all.
>> Amen. Amen. from Majesca. I was praying
a financial blessing and I was praying
for a strong faith and he blessed me
right where I needed it. From Jerry
Harvey Leonard, we won this round in
court. More rounds to come but won this
one. Praise him.
>> Amen.
>> We are cheerleading for that for sure.
From Jamie A. Praise report. Tammy and
her little ones have found housing.
>> Praise God.
from Francis Grant. Family, I want to
give God the praise for his goodness and
mercies. Thank you so much for your
prayers. God hears and answers. I
present the case that my husband was
unable to be aroused and woke up. We
went to the hospital and after a couple
of hours after we got to the emergency
room, he woke up. Nevertheless, as a
precaution, he was admitted to the
hospital. He had a repeat of the same
episode, but again the Lord intervened,
touched and fully woke him up and
restored him to his normal
consciousness.
After testing, the medical team finally
discovered that he had had a small
stroke and an infection. He is being
being treated for this and progressing
very well. They also discovered that the
medication he had been taking for years
that his body had been rejecting it all
along. and the med medication was unable
to do what it was supposed to do.
>> This appears to be the culprit for all
these unusual problems. He is a rare
case as he is one in a thousand that
this occurs in. If he hadn't gotten
sick, this would not have been
discovered and corrupted.
>> We can see the Lord's hand upon my
husband, and he's working all things out
to his perfect good. Yes,
>> because of God's grace and mercy, my
husband does not show any deficiencies
from the stroke. It is anticipated for
him to be released in the next few days
and sent to the rehabilitation center.
The Lord is awesome. To God alone
belongs all the praise, honor, and
glory. Hallelujah. Amen. Thank you again
for your prayers and for lift lifting us
up before the Lord.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. and Henrietta
uh Mubako. Wow. You had sepsis in
January and the Lord healed you. Praise
God for you, my beloved. Praise God.
Wow.
>> Praise God, Henrietta. It is no joke.
It's a little scary.
But God is good.
>> Yes, he is all the time. All the time.
>> This last praise report, I must say,
when I first read it, my jaw dropped to
the floor.
Um, this one comes from Stacy Ferguson.
I was jumped during COVID by a man and a
woman on meth.
>> I was maed in the face and beaten with a
2x4.
I cried out to God during the attack to
help me. And the reason I am alive today
is because God sent a neighbor to come
save my life. I was recently told the
man who attacked me has come to Christ.
The owner of the Sober Living Home and
his wife would like to bring the young
man over to apologize to me very soon.
Please pray for God to give me strength
to face this man again and to forgive
him.
>> Yes.
>> Please pray for the salvation of his
former girlfriend who is still on drugs.
>> Amen. Amen. Praise God. Well, Stacy,
I heard that you um will be giving your
full testimony about this situation on
an upcoming Power Wednesday. So, we look
forward to hearing
>> yes,
>> this testimony in full and we are so
grateful and thankful to God for sparing
your life. You are here for a reason and
we pray that you will have the strength
to face him. Um,
>> amen.
>> And forgive. Yeah.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> The word of God says that uh when a man
or woman's ways please the Lord, he
maketh even his enemies to be at peace
with him. And and what a better way to
make a get rid of your enemy than to
make them your friends. And uh that
that's the miracle of the new birth, the
miracle of Jesus in our lives that we
can actually love and forgive and pray
for those enemies that have hurt us.
That's the love of God. because when we
were his enemies, what did he do for us?
So, thank the Lord for his goodness
today, saints. And we are getting ready
to go to the throne of grace and want to
thank everybody. I see your prayers
requests are still coming in. We're
we'll be praying for your friend, Sister
Carla Den, uh dealing with an illness
and the doctors can hardly can identify
what that bug is. Yeah, I saw your
prayer request come up and it
disappeared, but now I see you put it
back. We'll be praying for him. And I
want to just send this to you all as we
get ready to go to the throne of grace.
Ammer and I started uh in our evening
Bible studies, we started going through
um the book of Samuel and we're kind of
studying the life of David. And earlier
in the week, the Lord laid something on
my heart. Uh when God wanted to send a
word to Eli, we know the story of Eli
and his sons. The Bible says that there
was a man of God that came to Eli.
doesn't give the man's name or anything,
but the man gave the prophecy to Eli,
and every word that that man spoke came
to pass.
>> Amen.
>> Much like Samuel, not one of those words
fell to the ground. But this man didn't
have any names mentioned, seeming in
insignificant and irrelevant.
And and and and what the Lord laid on my
heart about that is this. Someone
watching, it may be you. Listen, God's
purpose for your life is greater than
any accomplish, any title, any position,
any influence you might have. Whatever
God's purpose for your life is, nobody
may not ever know your name. You might
not ever be in the spotlight. You might
not ever uh be flashed up on the
billboard or you may not ever be on
splashed all across social media, but
God has a purpose for your life.
Somebody watching that's in his word.
And and I tell you, not one thing he's
planned for you will fail as long as you
put your life in his hands. I want to
encourage you today. We want to
encourage you. We're praying for you
today. Hold on. Don't let it go. Don't
give up. Don't give in. The world we're
living in right now will tempt all of us
to want to strive and scratch and pull
and fight for something that heaven has
already given to us and the blood of
Jesus has already purchased. What God
has for you is yours.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. So be strong and be
encouraged. uh
>> Carla Dim and Georgia Georgie Bruce, we
see your prayer requests. If for some
reason we are not able to pray over
specific
um prayers in the chat because they came
in too late, please know that our prayer
warriors are on it. They are recording
it and you will be prayed over all week
long. And Leon, we love you too.
>> Hey, love you my brother. Love you. Love
you likewise. and um and Georgia um
Bruce, your prayer request for the Bruce
family who just lost a godly husband,
father, brother, and uncle and friend,
we will definitely be praying right now.
Lord, bring comfort to that family.
>> And and and and again, as the Lord just
laid it on our hearts to say to you, no
matter what you are going through, no
matter what has happened to you or what
you have done in in him, in him you are
complete. You're complete in him and
everything he has for you is yours. no
matter what you go through. So hold on,
saints and be encouraged. Sister Karen
Johnson, we're praying for strength and
encouragement for you today. Sister
Jamie from Compton, we're praying for
your sister Tracy deliverance and some
issues in her family and in her I mean
in her life. We're praying for that and
complete healing with her. Brother
Jonathan felt that you're being pulling
pulled away. Let me tell you something.
Jesus says, "All the father had given to
me will come to me. No one will snatch
them out of my hand." You belong to the
master, brother Jonathan. We encourage
you to hold on. Sister Regina B, we are
praying for your mother, uh, Sister
Esther Lita White, uh, for healing and
for encouragement in her life. Um, Mimi,
we will be praying for your brother
who's just been diagnosed with brain
cancer. Lord have mercy. We will
definitely keep that lifted in prayer.
Uh, Sister Anetta Carr, we'll be praying
for Zayen, who will be 13 on October
3rd. Happy birthday, Zayen. Don't know
if you're watching, but we're
celebrating your beautiful life. praying
for your mental health and spiritual
well-being and um uh uh that you would
uh hear the voice of God and respond to
that beautiful word he has for you.
We're also praying for Courtney who's 12
years old and entering into high school.
Brilliant, brilliant young mind there.
So, we're praying God uh be with him and
keep them in you for s for you sister
Anetta. We know you're going through
chemo and so we'll be praying that God
will bless and heal you completely.
>> Amen.
>> In Jesus name. And so we also want to
pray for the saints of the most high God
particularly in this remnant movement.
Whether you're part of this remnant
movement or not or you're coming in, you
feel God's calling you. We're praying
that you will be able to hear,
recognize, and identify dragon speak and
avoid that. And once that happens, we
know that God will begin to unite his
people. So we're praying that uh you
will hear the word and listen to the
word that God is speaking. That's my
special prayer request for the church.
Want to pray for brother Taj and
Reflections of Hope and all of the
beautiful people of Hawaii. Hope you're
watching today. We love you. We're
praying for you and may God continue to
bless and lead, heal, move in every way
in your lives. Uh uh Sister Wendy Allen,
we're praying for you and your
grandchildren and God will continue to
bless and move in their hearts. Um pro
prosperous Kenua, you have a sensation
in the back of your throat. you went and
had that that that that scan and they
didn't find anything. But we'll pray
that God will definitely bring you
comfort and bring you healing. He knows
exactly what's going on there. Brother
Tom and Sister Joyce Fisher, we're
definitely praying for your church
family. Praying for your whole family.
And for this young woman who's confused
and uh not sure about what to do with
the unborn baby and whether to keep it
or destroy it, we're praying God it will
move in compassion and mercy and work
miracles in your lives and in her life
and in the church family's life. Um
also, Sister Barbara Edwards, we're
praying for your husband that's in the
hospital on a breathing tube right now.
May God bless, heal, touch, save, and
deliver in that area. And brother Artel
Peters, your Bible reading partner. Uh,
brother Moathaniel is unhoused and we're
praying that God will get put a roof
over his head and bless him and move in
his life in a special way. And AR,
my beloved AR, we we're praying for you.
You're praying for spiritual guidance
and you were praying that um God would
lead you to a church, a new church home,
whether it be physical, whether it be
online. And as the Lord spoke to you in
the chat earlier, he has always had a
special place and a purpose for your
life. And he's leading you into that
right now. You just keep right on
holding on, keep worshiping, keep loving
him, keep listening to him, and he'll
bring you to where you want to be. If
it's living manner, welcome to the
family, beloved.
>> Amen. There's a few more that came in.
>> Okay.
>> Tony George, pray for my confidence in
my academics. I have two more months
before I graduate with my bachelor
degree in social work. You are on the
home stretch. Amen.
>> You got this. You got this. You got
this. Nadia says, "Pray for my son
Thomas to have a closer walk with the
Lord." Thank you. We will deal. We will
do it indeed.
>> Karen Cook, "Please pray for my sister
Jennifer who had brain surgery three
weeks ago but hasn't woken up. Thank you
always for your faithfulness."
Um, please Oh, you got Nadia Nicole
Spartan 458. Please pray for demons are
oppressing me in my life. And pray for
my chicken Emity that she sleeps
peacefully and not get eaten by foxes.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amanda S. can you please pray for me and
my son Zion's salvation? Time is very
short. I've been very, very sick for
many years, but I'm realizing our
spiritual healing is more important. We
desperately need Jesus.
>> Amen. Sister Jod, we're praying for your
dad's conversion. Amen. and in physical
health and that uh and for your son's
conversion as well. Amen. Amen.
>> Amanda S. also pray for my vision. I am
losing my eyesight due to health issues.
Andre Ward, pray for my girlfriend with
her walk with God. I do want to go back
really really quick. I'm so sorry.
>> And on brother Andre, we didn't forget.
We prayed for her last week. So, and
we're not gonna stop. We don't forget.
Warriors don't forget. God lays it on
our heart and we keep it there. Nicole
Spartan 458. Let me That was This was
precious little prayer request right
there. We're praying for your chicken.
Yes.
>> That the foxes won't get your chicken.
That's right. Amen.
>> Carla Dim, please pray for my friend.
He's dealing with an illness. The
doctors can't identify what the bug is.
And I ask that you pray the doctors to
discover what that is.
And I think Oh, one last one before
Terry goes into prayer. Ellis and Lisa
Santiago pray for my three adult
children that have lost their way. May
God give them wisdom and understanding.
Again, if we did not catch your prayer
request, they will be caught by the
prayer warriors and disseminated out.
So, you will be prayed over and uh may
the Lord bless all of you.
>> Amen. Amen. And listen, y'all know how
prayer warriors are. You keep putting
them in that chat. We can't. So, I'm
just going to turn my head from that
screen. I'm not even gonna look back
over there and sister Jerry just typed
in the chat for her daughter to find a
job. We got we're gonna pray for See I
you you we even look and still getting
them. But I want to thank God for y'all.
We love y'all. Thank God for calling us
and giving us the opportunity to serve
in this capacity. Thank you for praying
for us as we're praying for you. Amen.
>> And thank you that we have a God who
hears and answers prayer. Prayer is an
amazing thing. It is our lifeline to
glory by that through prayer we breathe
the atmosphere of heaven. And God is
already moving saints. So let's go
together joining our faith in our hearts
and we will be praying for the living
word of God that's coming forth in just
a moment. Precious father in the name of
Jesus. Lord, we thank you. Lord, we
praise you. We lift you up and we
magnify you. Lord, we come to the throne
of grace worshiping. We come to the
throne of grace rejoicing. Lord, even
with tears in our eyes and burdens in
our hearts, Lord God, concerns, Lord
God, and temptations and tempted to
fear, tempted to worry, tempted to
doubt, Lord God. Tempted to give up and
throw in the towel, Lord God. Tempted to
throw it out, Lord, we are coming before
you with all we are and all we have
because none other have we in heaven
beside you. None on earth we desire
beside you. You are our hope, Lord God.
You are our dwelling place, Lord God.
You're our hope in ages past. You're our
rock, our refuge, our fortress, our high
tower, our shield, an exceeding great
reward. Lord God, our refuge and our
strength, our all in all, our friend
that stickketh closer than a brother,
water when we're thirsty, bread when
we're hungry, oh Lord God, your
physician when we're sick, Lord, our
healer, Lord God, you, Jesus, and we
give you the glory and the honor and the
praise that the blood has not lost its
power. Still sufficient, Lord God. still
able to heal, still able to save, still
able to touch and deliver. Thank you
that you're the same yesterday, today,
and forever. Thank you that you're the
same Jesus that walked those streets
healing and touching all who were sick
and oppressed of the devil because God
was with you and still is to this day.
And we want to give you glory, honor,
and praise, Father, because you said you
would never leave us nor forsake us, oh
God. And so we want to thank you today,
Lord, that our trials are not greater
than you. Our trials are not greater
than your purpose and plan for our life.
Thank you that your destiny that you
have assigned for our life and appointed
for our life will come to pass. Thank
you that you are alpha and omega. God,
thank you that you're the captain of the
sea. Hallelujah. Thank you that winds
and waves got to be still when you speak
peace into our lives. Oh Lord, in Jesus
name. But oh God, we pray Lord God in
Jesus name that whatever your purpose is
for these things that are going on in
our life, if they're going to bring us
to that expected end, then bring us on
through in Jesus name. Lord, I pray that
hope will fill the hearts and the minds
of your people. I pray that our eyes
would be open, our ears would be alert
and attentive, that our hearts would be
broken and surrendered before you, oh
Lord, in Jesus name. Let us not be
deceived. Let our minds not be defeated
by the devil and his lies. Lord, give us
a love for you and for your kingdom.
Give us a love for truth. Lord, that we
not fall under the strong delusion that
is in the atmosphere right now. This
deadly taint, this masma that the enemy
has spread into the atmosphere, Lord
God, in Jesus' name. Establish your word
in our hearts and fix us in your word.
For we are people of the word and a
people of the book and the people of
prophecy which you have foretold Lord
God which you have ordained which you
have established which you have planted
in this world today God. And Father we
know that though we come against giants,
Goliaths. We come in the name of the
Lord God of hosts. And we thank you for
that God being with us Lord God and
keeping us not for our sake but for your
name's sake. And because we are called
by your name. Thank you for forgiving us
for our sins. Thank you for having mercy
on us, Lord, when we rebelled against
you and when we turned our back against
you, when we were stubborn and didn't
listen. Thank you that your mercy is
greater. Thank you that your grace is
greater than all of our sins.
Hallelujah. And we just give you praise
right now. Fill us with the Holy Ghost
and power, Lord God. Wash away and and
blow away all of the chaff and all that
which is ungodly, which is not like you,
Lord, and bring us closer to you, Lord.
In Jesus' name we pray. And we thank
you, Lord. and for the word that is
about to come forth. Lord, you have been
so faithful and so good. Time and time
again, you've spoken through your
servant who you have raised up for such
a time as this. Thank you for Pastor Iva
Meyer and our first lady and the Meyers
family. Thank you that you have raised
them up as vessels of honor for such a
time as this. We see it, Lord. We know
it, Lord. We sense it. We see it.
There's evidence of it that you are
using this movement for a time Lord for
something special to make a difference
to be a voice in the earth and for that
we give you glory Lord we give you honor
and we give you praise and so as you
bring forth that word today Lord may our
hearts be attentive may our minds be
alert and oh God may we in everything
not about being right or being wrong or
having all the answers in everything
that we do and that we say may people
look upon us and see Jesus We give you
the glory, honor, and praise for hearing
and answering these prayers today, Lord.
Amen.
>> Amen.
[Music]
Great is thy faithfulness.
Oh God my father,
there is no shadow
of turning
away.
Thou changest
not the compassions
they fail mine
as thou has been thou forever
will be.
Great is thy faithfulness.
Morning by morning,
new mercies
I see.
All I have needed
thy hand and proide it.
Great is thy faithfulness
ptoe.
[Music]
for sitting.
Peace that
thine own dear presence to cheer it to
God.
Strength for today it bright
for tomorrow.
Blessings
all mine in 10,000.
[Music]
Great is thy faithfulness.
Morning
by morning,
new mercies
I see.
[Music]
All I have needed
thy hand and proide it.
Great is thy faithfulness.
Great is the faithfulness
to
me.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat
up here.
up
here.
[Music]
Amen. Amen. Uh happy Sabbath everyone.
Welcome to Living Manor online. Uh we
have a um uh by the grace of God uh a
message that
um
is very needed
and by the grace of God will bring dry
bones together.
Um praise God for that opening trailer
and we are about to get into the word uh
today. So put a one in the chat if you
are ready ready to uh to eat.
The title of the message today
left Jesus
right Jesus.
Left Jesus
right Jesus. Let's pray. Heavenly father
please speak
to your people
in Jesus name we pray. Amen.
We're going to go to the screen.
We'll go to our first slide. Um,
please make sure that you share this
link as we begin this message. Let
people know that the sermon has begun
and uh and that we're going to eat and
um we're going to get into this word.
Left Jesus,
right? Jesus.
In the book of first kings chapter 3
uh verse 5, the Bible
records these words in Gibian. The Lord
appeared to Solomon in a dream by night.
And God said, "Ask what I shall give
thee." And Solomon said, "Thou has
showed unto thy servant David, my
father, great mercy, according as he as
he has walked before thee in truth
and in righteousness, and in uprightness
of heart with thee." And thou has given
him, thou has kept for him this great
kindness, that thou has given him a son
to sit on his throne, as it is this day.
And now, oh Lord my God, thou has made
thy servant king instead of David my
father, and I am but a child. I know not
how to go out or come in. And thy
servant is in the midst of thy people,
which thou has chosen, a great people,
that cannot be numbered, nor counted for
multitude.
Give therefore thy servant an
understanding heart to judge thy people,
that I may discern
between good and evil. For who is able
to judge this thy so great a people? And
the speech pleased the Lord that Solomon
had asked this thing.
And God said unto him, "Because thou
hast asked this thing, and has not asked
for thyself long life, neither has asked
riches for thyself, nor has asked the
life of thine enemies, but has asked for
thyself understanding to discern
judgment.
Behold,
I have done according to thy works. Lo,
I have given thee a wise and
understanding heart, so that there was
none like thee before. Neither after
thee shall any arise like unto thee.
And I I've also given thee that which
thou hast not asked, both riches and
honor,
so that there shall not be any among the
kings like unto thee all thy days. And
if thou will walk in my ways to keep my
statutes and my commandments as thy
father David did walk,
then I will lengthen
thy days.
And Solomon awoke, and behold, it was a
dream. And he came to Jerusalem and
stood before the ark of the covenant of
the Lord and offered up a burnt offering
and offered peace offerings and made a
feast to all his servants.
We are living in a time
in which wisdom
is required.
Wisdom has always been required for
God's people.
But especially
as we come closer and closer to the
second coming of the Lord, wisdom is
more needed than ever.
The Bible tells us in Daniel 12:3, for
example, it says here, "Many will be and
they that be wise shall shine as the
brightness of the firmament, and they
that turn many to righteousness as the
stars
forever."
Daniel 12 chapter 10 or 12:10 rather
says many shall be purified
and made white and tried but the wicked
shall do wickedly and none of the wicked
shall understand
but the wise
shall understand.
We are living in a time where wisdom
is needed.
Wisdom allows us to discern between good
and evil. You see Solomon in his prayer,
he's asking the Lord for wisdom so that
he can discern between good and evil.
And in today's day, as evil is
progressing, as evil is growing, we need
wisdom to discern what is good and what
is evil.
Especially at the end of time where we
understand that the greatest deception
will be pulled upon the whole world.
Spoken of in Revelation 13:14
where it says that this power deceiveth
them that dwell on the earth by the
means of those miracles which he had
power to do in the sight of the beast,
saying to them that dwell on the earth
that they should make an image to the
beast, which had a wound by the sword
and did live. We understand here that
whatever this power is which is
ultimately a satanic power which will
ultimately culminate
with Satan himself appearing as Jesus.
We are going to need wisdom
to know the difference between goodness
and error,
between truth,
light and darkness,
between the real Jesus
and the counterfeit Jesus.
Wisdom will be required. And so the book
of James chapter 1 tells us gives us
encouraging words. It actually says,
"If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask
of God that giveth to all men liberally
and uprath not, and it shall be given
him." Just as Solomon asked for wisdom,
we too may ask for wisdom. And the Bible
says that God will give it. The other
reason wisdom is needed, we're told in
Proverbsap 1:7, "The fear of the Lord is
the beginning of knowledge, but fools
despise wisdom and instruction."
Wisdom is going to be required not only
for us to stand at the end of time.
for us to be able to discern between
that which is good and that which is
evil. But wisdom is the beginning of the
fear of the Lord or the fear of the Lord
is the beginning of knowledge or wisdom.
In order for us to stand in the last
days, we're going to need wisdom.
We're going to need wisdom. put up one
in the chat if you raise your hand today
to say, "Lord, give me wisdom." Those
who don't have wisdom, the Bible likens
in Matthew 7 26 with these words.
And everyone that hear these sayings of
mine and doeth them not shall be likened
unto a not a wise man, but a foolish
man, which built his house upon the
sand. and the rain descended and the
floods came and the winds blew and beat
up on that house and it fell and great
was the fall of it.
We're going to need wisdom in the last
days, not only to discern the true
Christ from the false Christ,
but even to discern true Christianity
from false Christianity. The Bible tells
us
uh in Matthew chapter chapter uh 7 that
not all who say Lord Lord
will enter into the kingdom of heaven.
The Bible says that only those who do
the will of God will enter into the
kingdom of heaven. So in essence in the
last days especially there will be a
counterfeit Christianity, a counterfeit
Jesus.
And if we don't have the wisdom, we will
not be able to discern between that
which is good and that which is bad,
that which is light and that which is
darkness. Are y'all with me so far?
In light of this,
the verses we just read in First Kings
sets us up for the actual demonstration
of why wisdom is needed. Let's go back
to the screen and we will pick up where
we left off. We're now in verse 16. So
remember Solomon has
woken up. It was a dream that he had.
And in the dream, God has given him
wisdom. He goes to Jerusalem. And he's
standing he's standing
uh um
giving up or or they're giving up
offerings to God as a celebration. The
ark of the covenant is mentioned. Please
keep that in mind. And then we read this
event taking place. The Bible says,
"Then came there two women that were
harlots
unto the king and stood before him. And
the one woman said,"Oh my Lord, I and
this woman dwell in one house, and I was
delivered of a child with her in the
house. And it came to pass the third day
after that I was delivered, that this
woman was delivered also, and we were
together. And there was no stranger with
us in the house, save we too in the
house."
And this woman's child died in the night
because she overlaid it. And she arose
at midnight and took my son from beside
me while thine handmade slept and laid
it in her bosom and laid her dead child
in my bosom.
And when I arose in the morning to give
my child suck, behold, it was dead. But
when I considered it in the morning,
behold, it was not my son which I did
bear. And the other woman said, "Nay,
but the living is my son, and the dead
is thy son." And this said, "No, but the
dead is thy son, and the living is my
son." Thus they spake before the king.
Then said the king, "The one saith, this
is my son that liveth, and thy son is
dead." And the other saith, nay, but thy
son is the dead, and my son is the
living. And the king said, "Bring me a
sword." And they brought a sword before
the king.
And the king said, "Divide
the living child into two,
and give half to the one,
and half to the other."
Then spake the woman, whose the living
child was, unto the king, for her bowels
yearned upon her son. And she said, "Oh
my lord, give her the living child, and
in no wise, slay it." But the other
said, "Let it be neither mine nor thine,
but divide it." Then said the king, Then
the king answered and said, "Give her
the living child, and in no wise slay
it, she is the mother thereof."
How many of you are familiar with this
story?
You've read this story before. You've
heard this story before.
In this story,
two women come before the king.
And in the story, they both are claiming
that the son belongs to them.
Let me say it again.
They both claim that the son the son
the son belongs to them.
Somebody is not telling the truth.
And the one who is not telling the truth
is acting so well that Solomon in all
his wisdom cannot discern who is lying
and who is telling the truth.
So the woman says, "My child, I I went
to sleep. This woman's child, she she
she
smothered her child basically and the
child died." And then she switched her
child for my child
and this is an injustice.
And then they both start going before
the king. No, the child is mine. No, the
child is mine. And Solomon in all his
wisdom cannot discern who is telling the
truth and who is lying.
Let's break this down, you guys. Are
y'all ready?
In the story, there are two women.
Two women.
I want you to notice with me in
Ephesians chapter 5:2 where the Bible
says, "Husbands, love your wives even as
Christ also loved the church and gave
himself for it." I want you to
understand here that in the Bible, a
woman is often used symbolically of a
church. And in light of that analogy,
I'm going to bring that analogy into the
text.
And so what I'm sharing with you beloved
today is I'm using this story to simply
say to you that in the world there are
two types of Christians.
Two types of Christians
both claiming
that they possess
the son.
Now, we understand that these two women
may very well represent two churches,
two different types of churches, but for
the sake of our study today, both the
women were in one house. So, we're going
to be talking just about in the church
of God, there are two different types of
Christians, both claiming
to possess the son. when in reality only
one really possesses the son. Only one
really possesses Jesus Christ. And this
brings us right back to the point we
made a little bit earlier in Matthew 7
21 where the Bible says,
"Not everyone that saith unto me, Lord,
Lord, shall enter into the kingdom of
heaven, but he that doeth the will of my
father which is in heaven." Many will
say to to me in that day, Lord, Lord,
have we not prophesied in thy name? and
in thy name cast out devils and in thy
name done many wonderful works and then
will I profess unto them I never knew
you depart from me you that work
iniquity there are two types of
Christians in the church and and both
claim to have Jesus but only one really
has Jesus only one really has the son
and remember now Solomon in all his
wisdom cannot tell the difference both
women seem sincere both women are
probably weak weeping. Both women seem
moved with passion for the son, but one
is insincere.
Let's talk about it.
The woman that lost her child lost her
child because she was careless.
The text says, let's read it again. And
this woman's child died in the night
because she overlaid it. She slept
She slept on Jesus.
She slept on the son.
She was careless with her relationship
with Jesus. Many of us, beloved, are
careless in our relationship with
Christ. We're not taking care of him.
We're not taking care of the
relationship the way we are supposed to.
And so what happens is while men slept,
I mean while we sleep,
it is amazing while we sleep
the enemy is able to come in and switch
out Jesus's on us.
First Kings chapter 3 20. Let me read it
again. And she rose at midnight and took
my son from beside me while thine
handmade slept and laid it in her bosom
and laid her dead child in my bosom. And
when I arose in the morning to give my
child suck, behold, it was dead. But be
but when I considered in the morning,
behold, it was not my son which I did
bear. Beloved, we got to be careful. We
have to be careful not to sleep on Jesus
because if we do, I guarantee you the
enemy will come in and switch him out.
switch out a counterfeit Jesus.
The enemy wants to switch Jesus's with
us.
Hold that thought for a moment. Hold
that thought for a moment.
First Kings chapter 3 23. And the other
woman said, "Nay, but the living is my
son, and the dead is thy son." And they
said, "No, but the dead is thy son, and
the living is my son." Thus they spake
before the king. Then said the king, the
one saved, this is my son that liveth,
and thy son is dead. And the other save,
nay, but thy son is the dead, and mine's
the living. And the king said, bring me
a sword. And they brought a sword before
the king. And watch this now. The king
said, "Divide the living child in two."
And gave half to the one and half to the
other.
The woman who's
who did not have a relationship with the
son responds,
"Let it be neither mine nor thine, but
divided."
The woman who did not really possess the
child was content to divide the body.
Let me say it again.
Let me say it again. The woman who did
not have a relationship with the child
was cool
was fine
with half with dividing the body.
Now what does dividing the body mean? It
means there would be a left side of the
body
and a right side of the body. Let's just
look at it like that. A left side of the
body and a right side of the body.
Do you know that in the church today
there are two Jesuses?
There is the left Jesus
and there is the right Jesus.
Are you Are y'all ready? I'm not sure if
you're ready for this, but you're going
to have to be because we're dealing with
some very unfortunate realities
in the church, beloved. There is a left
Jesus and there is a right Jesus.
Many Christians in the church possess
the spirit of this woman who says, "Let
it be divided.
Let it neither be whole. Let it neither
be mine or thine, but just let it be
divided."
So let's talk about left Jesus first
because many of us have accepted a left
Jesus
that that at first seems good. Let's
talk about left Jesus. Come on. So left
Jesus has some very good qualities. Left
Jesus uh h uh lives on verses like
these. Let's go to the screen. Luke 4 18
and 19. The spirit of the Lord is upon
me because he has anointed me to preach
the gospel to the poor. He has sent me
to heal the brokenhearted, to preach
deliverance to the captives and
recovering of sight to the blind, to set
at liberty them that are bruised, to
preach the acceptable year of the Lord.
Left Jesus loves the oppressed. Left
Jesus is concerned about about the
oppressed and about those who are
captive. This is very appealing. Left
Jesus is appealing. left. This is left
Jesus's verse. Come on, let's go back to
the screen. Let's go. Matthew chapter
25. Matthew 25:35 and 36. This is left
Jesus for I was hungered and you gave me
meat. I was thirsty and you gave me
drink. I was a stranger and you took me
in. Naked and you clothed me. I was sick
and you visited me. I was in prison and
you came unto me. Left Jesus thrives on
these verses. These verses are verses of
compassion. left. Jesus thrives thrives
on Matthew 25:40. In as much as you've
done it unto the least of these, my
brethren, you have done it unto me.
Isaiah 1:17, learn to do well, seek
judgment, relieve the oppressed, judge
the fatherless, plead the widow, plead
the widow. How about this? Uh Micah 6:8.
But he has shown thee, oh man, what is
good. And what does the Lord require of
thee but to do justly and to love mercy
and to walk humbly with thy God. There's
Amos 5:24. Let judgment run down as
waters and righteousness as mighty
streams. And and James 1:27, pure
religion and undefiled before God and
the father is this to visit the
fatherless and widows in their
affliction and to keep him himself
unspotted from the world. And how about
this one? Proverbs 31:8 and 9. Open thy
mouth for the dumb in the cause of all
such are appointed to destruction. Open
thy mouth, judge righteously, and plead
the cause of the poor and the needy.
Beloved,
there are some good things about left
Jesus. If I were to ask you right now,
how many of you are liking how left
Jesus sounds? How many of you would say,
"Man, I love this Jesus." I love left
Jesus. put a one in the chat if you
would say, "Hey, man. I this I love this
Jesus."
And and so you would think, well, who
would have a problem with left Jesus?
Left Jesus is good Jesus. But hold on,
there are others in the church
who have right Jesus.
Right Jesus.
You take your half of Jesus and I'm
going to take my half of Jesus. there.
There's some reason that they don't like
left Jesus.
Right Jesus doesn't like left Jesus
and left Jesus doesn't like right Jesus.
Are y'all following me?
Please y'all please just just Okay.
So, please follow along and please
let's not let's not put anyway
guys please be respectful in the chat.
I'm asking you I'm asking you please be
respectful in the chat. No, right Jesus.
Right Jesus.
There are good attributes about right G.
Let's talk about right Jesus. Right
Jesus says stuff like this. Matthew
7:21. Not everyone that saith unto me,
Lord, Lord, shall enter into the kingdom
of heaven, but he that doeth the will of
my father which is in heaven. Right
Jesus is all about doing the right thing
and doing what the word says. Right
Jesus, but as first Peter 1:15, but as
he which has called you as holy, so be
ye holy in all manner of conversation
because it is written, "Be ye holy, for
I am holy." Right? Jesus is about living
right. Holiness, right? Jesus loves
verses like these. Hebrews 12:14,
"Follow peace with all men and holiness
without which no man shall see the
Lord." Right? Jesus sounds pretty good
to me, guys. Write Jesus. Here is the
patience of the saints. here they keep
the commandments of God and have the
faith of Jesus. It's about doing right
with right Jesus.
Ecclesiastes 12:13, let us hear the
conclusion of the whole. Yes, that's
right. Thank you, Paul. Let's not put
names out there, please. Right. Jesus
says, let us hear the conclusion of the
whole matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments, for this is the whole duty
of man. That's right, Jesus. Right.
Jesus says, the statutes of the Lord are
right, rejoicing the heart. The
commandments of the Lord is pure,
enlightening the eyes. The fear of the
Lord is clean, enduring forever. The
judgments of the Lord are true and
righteous all together. This is right
Jesus. Right Jesus. Right Jesus.
Hold on.
Pause for a second.
How many of you think right Jesus sounds
pretty good? Put a one in the chat if
you're like, man, this right Jesus, he's
all about business. He sounds good. That
right Jesus sounds good.
Left Jesus sounds good.
Right Jesus sounds good.
But you see, beloved, there is a problem
with left Jesus. There is a deep down
dark problem with left Jesus.
Let's talk about left Jesus's problems
first.
You see,
left Jesus isn't too concerned about
obedience.
Left Jesus loves the sinner but is
unconcerned about the sin.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you you
lock in on what I just said.
left Jesus
loves
the sinner
but is not at all concerned about the
sin
left Jesus says ah it's not really a sin
is it
left Jesus
ignores verses like these John 811
Jesus said unto her, "Neither do I
condemn thee. Go
and sin
no more." Left Jesus has radical
inclusivity without requiring
repentance.
Left Jesus ignores verses like these.
Fear God and keep his commandments for
this is the whole duty of man. Left
Jesus cares about justice for the
oppressed without accountability for
sin.
left. Jesus is is about mercy but is not
about judgment because he has appointed
a day in which he will judge the whole
world in righteousness by that man whom
he has ordained whereof he giveth
assurance unto all men in that he raised
him up from the dead. Left Jesus says
hey mercy is good but left Jesus isn't
too concerned about judgment.
Left Jesus ignores the fact that you
must be born again. In John 3:es 3-5,
the Bible says, "Jesus answered and said
unto him, verily, verily, I say unto
thee, except a man be born again, he
cannot enter the kingdom of God."
Nicodemus saith unto him, "How can a man
be born when he's old? Can he enter the
second time into his mother's womb and
be born?" Jesus said, "Verily, verily, I
say unto thee, except a man be born of
water and of the spirit,
he cannot enter the kingdom of God."
Left Jesus says, "Hey, you can be
forgiven, but you don't need to be
transformed." left. Jesus
is concerned about feeding the hungry
but ignores the bread of life.
The Bible says in 2 Timothy chapter
2:15, "Study to show thyself approved, a
workman that needeth not be ashamed of
the word of God." Study to show thyself
approved, a workman that needeth not be
ashamed of the word of God. the the the
left Jesus is more concerned with
feeding the hungry with bread than
feeding the hungry with the word.
John 6:35 Jesus said, "I am the bread of
life. He that cometh to me shall never
hunger. He that believeth on me shall
never thirst." Left Jesus celebrates
diversity
without discernment.
Romans 1:25-28, who changed the truth of
God into a lie, and worshiped and served
the creature more than the creator, who
is blessed forever, forever. Amen. For
this cause God gave them up unto vile
affections. For even their women did
change the natural use unto that which
is against nature, and likewise also the
men, leaving the natural use of the
woman, burned in their lust, one toward
another, men with men working that which
is unsemly, left. Jesus says, "Hey, this
verse doesn't really matter.
Left Jesus is nonjud non-judgmental to
the point of silence.
Left Jesus ignores this verse. Judge not
according to the appearance but judge
righteous judgment.
Are you with me? Are you following? Are
you understand? Left Jesus
has a tolerance for sin that is
disguised as love.
left. Jesus says um
left Jesus ignores Ezekiel 3:18. When I
say unto the wicked, thou shalt surely
die, and thou givest him not warning,
nor nor speaketh to warn the wicked from
his wicked way to save his life, the
same wicked man shall die in his
iniquity, but his blood will I require
at your hand.
left Jesus embraces a social aspect of
the gospel without connecting that
social aspect with the eternal gospel
which says in Revelation 14 6 and 7 I
saw another angel fly in the midst of
heaven having the everlasting gospel to
preach unto them that dwell on the earth
to every nation kindred tongue and
people saying with a loud voice fear God
and give glory to him for the hour of
his judgment is coming worship him that
made heaven and earth the sea and the
fountains of water
left Jesus wants peace without the
sword.
When Jesus said, "Think not that I am
come to send peace on the earth. I came
not to send peace but a sword." You see,
beloved, the problem with left Jesus is
that while left Jesus looks good, he is
not balanced.
Left Jesus is not really Jesus. It just
looks like Jesus.
left Jesus. Left. Okay, let me say it
this way. Right now, you can tell
if you have accepted left Jesus
if in your heart you're kind of
struggling right now with what is being
said about left Jesus.
If you're trying to protect left Jesus,
>> then that might be Jesus actually
speaking to you.
Because beloved left Jesus is not Jesus.
He may look like Jesus. Just like the
two women in the story. Hey, he's mine.
He's mine. But one woman was content
with half of Jesus. The other woman was
like, "No, no, no, no, no. I need all of
Jesus."
And so the question now for us is, "Hey,
do I really have all of Jesus or do I
just have left Jesus? Do I just have
right Jesus? Because just as there is a
dark side to left Jesus, there is a dark
side to right Jesus.
You see,
right Jesus
is a Republican.
Everybody knows that
right Jesus is Republican.
Who doesn't know that? Right Jesus uh uh
isn't too fond of the immigrants. Right
Jesus doesn't believe racism exists.
Right Jesus thinks that black people are
in high positions uh that aren't
qualified to be there. Black Jesus I'm
sorry.
Right Jesus is a communist hunter. Right
Jesus is a Marxist hater. Right Jesus is
anti-woke. Meaning anything that is
against right Jesus. That's what
anti-woke is. Right Jesus is anti-Dei
because right Jesus isn't about
diversity or inclusion or right Jesus
hates critical race theory because white
Jesus a right Jesus I'm sorry right
Jesus
erroneously thinks that critical race
theory teaches that all white people are
just racist.
Right Jesus is antivaccine
and now right Jesus right Jesus is now
anti- Tylenol.
You know that right?
Do y'all catch what I'm saying? Come on.
Put a one in the chat if you're like hey
I know right Jesus and I know left
Jesus. I've seen them both.
See? See? Let's go. Let's go to the
screen, y'all. Right. Jesus ignores
Right. Jesus ignores this this very
important thing. 1 Corinthians 13:2,
"And though I have the gift of prophecy
and understand all mysteries and all
knowledge, and though I have all faith
so that I can remove mountains and have
not charity, I am nothing." Right? Jesus
doesn't worry about love. Right? Jesus
only thinks about what he calls tough
love.
Right. Jesus is concerned with holiness
without mercy. Let's go back to the
screen where Jesus, the real Jesus,
said, "Woe unto you scribes and
Pharisees, hypocrites. For you pay tithe
of mint and annice and cumin, and have
omitted the weightier matters of the
law, judgment, mercy, and faith. These
you ought to have done, and not to have
left the other undone." Right? Jesus is
concerned about obedience, but doesn't
care about compassion. Matthew 9:13. But
go ye and learn what what this meanth. I
will have mercy and not sacrifice. For
I'm not come to call the righteous, but
sinners to repentance. Right Jesus is
all about the law, but doesn't think too
much about grace. For the law was given
by Moses, but grace and truth came by
Jesus Christ. Right Jesus is concerned
about judgment and doesn't care too much
about forgiveness. So right Jesus would
have stoned the woman caught in
adultery. Y'all get what I'm saying?
Right Jesus would have stoned the woman
caught in adultery and then rejoiced
about the stoning. Rejoiced about the
exposing.
Right? Jesus is more concerned with
religion than he is with relationship.
And so Jesus says, the real Jesus says,
"This people draweth nigh to me with
their mouth and honorth me with their
lips, but their heart is far from me. In
vain do they worship me, teaching for
doctrines the commandments of men."
Right? Jesus is all about zeal without
knowledge. For I bear them record that
they have a zeal of God, but not
according to knowledge. For they being
ignorant of God's righteousness, and
going about to establish their own
righteousness, have submitted
themselves, have not submitted
themselves unto the righteousness of
God.
Right? Jesus defends
cruelty
in the name
of Jesus.
They shall put you out of the
synagogues. Yay, the time cometh that
whosoever kill you will think he's doing
God's service. And these things they
will do unto you because they have not
known the Father nor known me.
Right? Jesus
doesn't care about righteousness, the
righteousness of Christ.
They ignore these verses. being found in
him, not having my own righteousness,
which is of the law, but that which is
through faith of Christ, the
righteousness which is of God by faith.
What I'm trying to tell you, beloved, is
that in a certain sense,
we have created God in our own image.
We have taken Jesus and said, "I am
content with left Jesus or I am content
with right Jesus." And now we literally
go through life thinking that Jesus is
actually in heaven a Republican,
in heaven a Democrat,
in heaven a leftist, in heaven a
rightist. We are, we literally believe
with all our How can you not see that
Jesus is a Republican? I I don't
understand. What are you, what are you
talking? Oh, are you not a Christian?
You must not be a Christian cuz you
don't know that Jesus is MAGA.
Don't you get that?
We have created Jesus in our own image.
So, so what's happening is
that people are walking around with half
of Jesus.
And if you have half of Jesus, you
really have none of Jesus.
Remember how the the the the text said
in Solomon how how he was before the ark
of the covenant? That's significant, you
guys, because I want you to notice
something about the ark of the covenant.
In Exodus 25:10 and 11, listen to this.
Exodus 25:10-11 the Bible says, "And
they shall make an ark of and wood.
Two cubits and a half shall be the
length thereof, and a cubit and a half
the breadth thereof, and a cubit and a
half the height thereof. And thou shalt
overlay it with pure gold within and
without shalt thou overlay it, and make
it a crown of gold round.
And thou shalt put into the ark of the
testimony which I shall give thee. Thou
shalt put into the ark the testimony
which I shall give thee.
and thou shalt make a mercy seat of pure
gold.
Let's stop right there.
Do you know that the ark of the
covenant,
that part of the ark of the covenant is
the mercy seat? Here's what happens,
beloved. Left Jesus says, "Give me the
mercy seat." Right? Jesus says, "Give me
the ark." You cannot separate that
article of furniture.
You can't do that. To do that is to be
content with half the child.
God demands justice and he also demands
mercy. God demands left and right of
Jesus.
Our appeal should not be give me half of
Jesus. It should be give me Jesus. All
of Jesus. All of Jesus. Many of us are
content with half of Jesus.
Many of us in the church are guilty of
worshiping right Jesus or left Jesus.
Not understanding that when you take the
good attributes of right Jesus and the
good attributes of left Jesus and bring
them together that is when you actually
have Jesus. So to have Jesus is a denial
of the right Jesus who says yes justice
and this is wrong and this is right
without caring about the oppressed. That
is not the the Jesus you have that
doesn't care about the immigrant, about
the oppressed, about the needy, that is
not Jesus. And the Jesus you have who
who cares about the oppressed and the
immigrant and all those things, but
hates righteousness, doesn't doesn't
expose sin, that is not Jesus.
And if you are content with half of
Jesus, you do not have Jesus at all.
And so,
and so
the king says in his wisdom, what? Come
on, y'all. Come on. Listen to this. The
king says in his wisdom, "Bring me a
sword."
Yes.
Just let me clap over here by myself for
a moment, y'all. Bring me a sword. Now,
listen y'all. Solomon is not about to
kill the child.
That's not who he is.
The reason he says, "Bring me a sword,"
is because the sword he knows is going
to reveal
who is the true mother and who isn't.
Come on, y'all. Come on. Come on. Come
on.
Bring me a sword.
Hebrews 4:12, "For the word of God, for
the word of God, for the word of God,
for the word of God, for the word of God
is quick and powerful and sharper than
any two-edged sword, piercing even to
the dividing a sunder of soul and
spirit, and of the joints and marrow,
and is a discerner of the thoughts and
intents of the heart." Solomon knows I
got to get I gotta get I got to get to
the to the thoughts and the intent of
these two women. So bring me a sword
because the word of God when fully
accepted reveals who is the true and who
is the false. Who really has a
relationship with Jesus and who doesn't?
And listen
Jesus is not condemning us here. He's
not saying ah you only have half half
Jesus you're lost. What he's trying to
show us is listen, you are walking
around with half Jesus thinking you're
converted and you're not. And I'm
revealing it to you so that you can get
all of Jesus.
This is exactly what's happening in the
Christian world today, beloved. So watch
this. The sword is the word of God. The
sword reveals what's really in our
hearts.
The sword is the whole word of God. Acts
20 27. Acts 20:27. Note what the text
says. For I have not shunned to declare
unto you all the counsel of God. All the
counsel of God. You see, beloved, the
real Jesus de the real Jesus is about
all the counsel of God. Left Jesus only
likes the verses about oppression and
being kind and being sweet. Right. Jesus
only likes the verses about judgment and
yes, abortion is wrong and all these
things. Left Jesus wants to point out
everything that is wrong. Right. Jesus
wants to point out all the all the
things that should be good. But beloved,
if we're not listen,
left Jesus,
left Jesus claims to be woke.
[Music]
left. Jesus,
claims to be woke
but is asleep to the word of God.
Right Jesus is anti-woke.
Meaning right Jesus is also asleep.
Because I need you to understand to be
anti-woke, to be anti-awwake is to be
asleep. Right? Jesus is sleeping and
left Jesus is sleeping.
And what the church needs now more than
ever is to present to the world a
picture of a Jesus
who is not left Jesus and is not right
Jesus.
And I used to think
that of all people, our church would be
the church that could say, "Hey guys,
listen. This is what's good about left
Jesus. This is what's good about right
Jesus." And in actuality, the real Jesus
is a combination of these things. But
no, in the church too, we have said,
"Hey, divide the child. Give me left
Jesus and I'm I'll be on my way. Give me
right Jesus and I'll be on my way.
There's another title to this message
which I cannot say yet, but I will say
as we get to that part.
We're getting there and I hope y'all are
sitting down.
Come on. First Kings chapter 3 26 and
27. Watch what happens. Then spake the
woman whose the living child was unto
the king, for her bowels yearned upon
her son. And she said, "Oh my lord, give
her the living child and in no wise slay
it." Then said the king and answered, or
then answered the king, and said, "Give
her the living child and in no wise slay
it. She is the mother thereof." Listen,
the true mother would rather sacrifice
herself than see the body the body the
body divided.
The true mother
was willing to sacrifice herself then
she would rather sacrifice herself than
see the body of the child. the body
divided.
Solomon's call for the sword was not to
to kill the child, to divide the body.
It was to reveal who truly cares about
the son.
And you know what's amazing? When the
true mother said, "No, don't harm the
child. Give her the child." Oh man, that
it is her child.
And the woman is willing to lose her
child that the child may live.
In this very thing, listen to me. In
this very thing, the woman actually
reveals justice in her cry.
Justice means giving each their due. So
the woman, the true mother acknowledges,
if the child must live, if the child
must live, even if it costs me my
rights, let justice be done for the
child.
The the true mother even in that cry was
revealing mercy because she could have
said, "Hey, divide the child and at
least give me half." But in her mind, no
mer this child needs mercy right now.
life is on the line. And if it requires
me losing what rightfully belongs to me,
I would rather mercy than have the child
die.
You guys understand this. This woman is
reflecting the whole Jesus. She's
reflecting the Jesus of justice, the
Jesus of mercy. She's reflecting in her
action exactly what Jesus is, who is
justice and mercy met in one.
You do understand beloved that the wages
of sin is death. You understand that?
According to Romans chapter 6 verse 23.
See it on the screen. The wages of sin
is death. And you do understand that a
sword was headed to us. But Jesus said
no no no.
Let me take the sword.
Zechariah 13:7. Awake oh sword against
my shepherd and against the man that is
my fellow. Sayith the Lord of hosts,
"Smite the shepherd, and the sheep shall
be scattered, and I will turn my hand
upon the little ones." Jesus took the
sword on our behalf.
Come on, y'all. Jesus took the sword on
our behalf so that we would not die, so
that we would not be divided. And if he
was willing to die on our behalf, that
that the body not be divided. How dare
we?
How dare we?
How dare we MAGA Adventists? How dare we
leftist Adventist? How dare we
divide the body that Christ died for to
bring together?
How dare we? The Bible says in Isaiah
53:5 and 6, "But he was wounded for our
transgressions. He was bruised for our
iniquities. The chastisement of our
peace was upon him, and with his stripes
we are healed. All we like sheep have
gone astray and have turned everyone his
own way. And the Lord laid on him
the iniquity of us all."
This is why, beloved, we're told in 1
John 4:19, we love him because what? He
first loved us,
a false Christian.
The Christians that are content
with half Jesus, God is trying to speak.
God's trying to speak.
He's trying to show us what is in our
hearts that we do not even know or
understand is there.
Because the heart is deceitfully wicked.
who can know it.
He's trying to appeal to us. There are
so many of us that that are in this
world where evil is growing by the day.
We are we are becoming engrossed and
and taking our eyes off of Jesus.
You guys listen to me.
The body should not be divided
over vaccines
or over race.
There is nothing that should divide the
body of Christ.
And you can almost see the hypocrisy
when a when a call was made last year to
divide the body because of religious
liberty and vaccines and blah blah blah.
There were people who were
because the church is an apostasy
anyway. The church is not the church is
the church is is it's no longer the
voice of of God on earth. And and and
there's corruption and and and and there
were these ju just hey it what's the big
deal?
Whole conferences are going to fall.
And last year when I said, "Hey, no, no,
no, no, no, no. Wrong move, you don't
know what you're talking about." And now
now
in in in light of certain events that
have taken place over the last several
weeks where you now have this issue of
race being brought up in the church and
questions and talk of, you know, should
we divide? Should we have, you know, a
black conference or a white conference?
I say, no, that's still not the answer.
I mean,
wow, what a what a slip up. Black
conferences and white conferences. I'll
get to that in a moment. Should we
separate based on on this? And I'm
saying no. The same people who were
cheering back then and saying, "Oh, this
is boldness. This is courage. We need to
stand." Are saying, "Well, how can you?
This is this is divisive and this is a"
And you know what? Trust me. Trust me.
Guess what's going to happen? Those who
follow right Jesus are going to be like,
"Well, you see the difference between
that and this is."
And those who follow left Jesus who are
cheering this on will say, "Well, the
difference between this and that was,"
and I'm telling you, I'm telling you,
you guys,
dividing the body
is never the answer.
That's what
Satan wants to do.
Last year when people were talking about
we need to boycott the GC and and we're
going to take our tithe and divert it
and people were chairing it and I said
no that's wrong. We we no we and
how dare you.
How dare you?
And when I say the same thing now,
regardless of what I believe is an
actual issue that needs to be addressed
in our church, I'm saying still the
issue needs to be addressed. Let's come
together and address the issue. But no,
division is not the answer.
And when I see that that people are
willing to divide and you got to
understand beloved, we might be we are
still a church but the division is
happening on a micro level because
people are splitting friendships. You
know how many you know how many friends
I've lost that I don't even know I've
lost yet?
friends who I have lost because because
they thought I was worshiping left
Jesus.
Anytime I spoke about, you know, we got
to stand for justice. Oh, you're left
Jesus. You don't believe that that you
know that that this is wrong or this is
wrong. And I'm like, when did I ever say
that? I don't believe this is wrong.
This is wrong. No, I it was just you're
left Jesus. You're right, Jesus.
And and so this division happening on
this micro level is people cutting
people off. I don't talk with them no
more. Why? cuz she's left Jesus. He's
left Jesus. He's right Jesus. She's
right Jesus. And people just stop
talking.
Sometimes you don't even know that
you've been unfriended till you're
running through your Facebook one day
and you're like, "Wait a minute. We were
Oh, we're not friends. Wow, man.
The division is happening on a micro
level, revealing that we are just like
the woman in this story.
Martin Luther King
said this. He said, "It is appalling
that the most segregated hour of
Christian America is 11:00 on Sunday
morning.
You see, beloved, we don't just have
left Jesus and right Jesus. There is
also black Jesus and white Jesus.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. The full title
of this message is actually left Jesus,
right Jesus, black Jesus, white Jesus.
What Martin Luther King said way back
then is still true today.
We still have black Jesus and white
Jesus.
Ella White said something that that's
really quite concerning.
Let me read to you what she said. I'm
just going to put them up on the screen.
Three or four quotes. In 1895, she said,
"Slavery will be revived again will be
revived in the southern states, for the
spirit of slavery still lives."
She also said, "The same spirit that
held the colored people in slavery is
not dead, but alive today and ready to
spring into action."
Once again,
she said, "In the South, the spirit of
slavery is not eradicated. It has only
been smothered for a short time." This
is 1899.
She also said in an interview, this
interview was recorded 1907.
She said, "Slavery, there will be
slavery just as verily 1907, you guys.
There will be slavery just as verily as
it has been only upon a basis that is
more favorable and secure to white
people.
PT man who she was speaking to responded
by saying more secure because they do
not feed they do not have to feed the
negroes or care for them. Then if the
negro has got outside that district or
if he is loafing and not working, they
can put him in the chain gang for a
year.
You understand what Ellen White was
saying here? Ellen White was prophesying
the promotion
of systemic racism
where slavery would just change its face
and would be more favorable, she says,
to the white people. This is Ellen White
speaking, y'all, not me. Not me.
Not all white people, she said. It's not
all she's talking about. But those whom
racism dwells in their hearts.
And the reason I bring this up, beloved,
is because because
I praise God
that the Adventist church is one of the
most diverse
churches in the world. How many of you
want to put a seven in the chat for
that? put a seven in the chat that you
say we praise God that the Adventist
church is one of the most diverse
churches in the world,
racially
diverse.
I praise God for that.
But I also need to talk about Lucy
Bayard,
who in 1943
became seriously ill and was taken to a
hospital, Washington Sanitarium,
um, in Tacoma Park.
And because she was light-skinned, they
thought she was white.
And then
when they found out she was black, they
told her that they could not serve her.
systemic racism
in the Adventist church
in 1943.
And what happened is that they she had
to go to another hospital and then she
actually died sometime later, short time
later. and her death was blamed
on
this racism.
And
as a result of this,
the body
was split.
We had the introduction of regional
conferences
because
of systemic racism
within the Adventist church.
That was 1944.
The body
was split.
The body was divided.
And we are now in 2025.
And what I'm saying to you, beloved, is
we cannot do this any longer.
The body of Christ must come together.
What that looks like, I don't know. I
don't have the answers. But here's what
I do know.
We cannot testify of the love of Jesus.
You understand? You see what's happened
in the last couple of weeks. You see how
race tensions are are are right they're
right there under the carpet.
And if we are not willing
to deal with the division,
the body will remain divided
between left Jesus, right Jesus, black
Jesus, white Jesus.
And then Ellen White has a statement
here that is a rebuke to us all.
Here's what she says.
In fact, let me read Genesis 1:26 first
and then I'm going to read what she
says. In Genesis 1:26, the Bible says,
"And God said, ' Let us make man in our
image, after our likeness, and let them
have dominion over the fish of the sea
and the foul of the air." Do you
understand, beloved, that what we have
done, what many of us have done is we
have said, "Let us make God in our image
and after our likeness."
Absolutely. Fathom.
Absolutely. Please understand, please
understand that the the start of
regional conferences was not black
people just saying we're going to go
start our own thing. We were black
people were begging for integration.
And the response was
and this is the legacy that we that we
carry right now.
It's a shameful legacy.
It's a shameful legacy. Here's what
Ellen White said,
and this is good news and bad news.
And I'm going to close this up, you
guys.
She said, "It will be impossible to
adjust all matters regarding the color
question in accordance with the Lord's
order until," Let me stop right there.
You guys, did you hear that just now?
Did you hear that just now? She said it
will be impossible to adjust all matters
regarding the color question in
accordance with the Lord's order until
beloved. That is good news.
Did you hear? Put in one in the chat if
you understand how good how good of a
news that is.
It will be impossible to adjust all
matters regarding the color question in
accordance with the Lord's order until
meaning that she saw it happening. She
said something is going to happen that
then it will happen.
The question is oh by the way yes right
Jesus hates the UN too. I forgot about
that. Right Jesus hates the UN.
You you guys the caricature of left
Jesus and right Jesus it just becomes
unfortunately so
laughable if it wasn't so sad
the social gospel.
What is that?
Did not Jesus say take care of your
neighbors, love others? How can right
Jesus degrade that as oh it's a social
gospel?
Are we not supposed to demonstrate the
beauty of the harmony of working for our
neighbors while also preaching the three
angels messages?
Have we not been called to be to call
sin out as it is and yet still be
merciful and gracious and kind and
loving and empathetic.
Let's go back to the statement.
It will be impossible to adjust all
matters regarding the color question in
accordance with the Lord's order until
those who believe the truth are so
closely united with Christ that they are
one with him.
Both the white and the colored members
of our churches need to be converted.
There are some of both classes who are
unreasonable
and when the color question is agitated
they manifest unsanctified
unconverted traits of character.
Quarrelome elements are easily aroused
in those who, because they have never
learned to wear the yoke of Christ, are
opinionated and obstinate. In such self
clamors with an unsanctified
determination for the supremacy.
Do y'all see what she just said?
The reason the color question still
exists in our church is because whenever
it's brought up, there are many who want
to deny it that it even exists. And
there are others
who through anger don't even want to
talk about it.
It just is what it is.
There's resentment.
Ellen White says that we need to be
converted
because when we are converted, we can
actually then deal with the question
and left Jesus will disappear from the
church and right Jesus will disappear
from the church and black Jesus will
disappear from the church and white
Jesus will disappear from the church and
we will we will be left with just Jesus.
Just Jesus.
All I want is Jesus. Not left Jesus. Not
right Jesus. Not black Jesus. Not white
Jesus. Jesus.
Jesus who loves everybody. Jesus who
loves the left, who loves the right, who
loves the black, who loves the white.
Jesus, the actual Jesus.
God is going to keep bringing us around
to this until we get it right. Why?
Because because
our closing statement,
Christ is waiting with longing desire
for the manifest manifestation of
himself in his church. Do y'all see it
on the screen?
Let me read it again. Christ is waiting
with longing desire for the
manifestation of himself in his church.
It's not up on the screen. I need y'all
to see this when with your own eyes.
All right. Maybe my slide is messed up.
Slide team.
All right. I'll just read it in your
hearing.
Christ is waiting with longing desire
for the manifestation of himself in his
church.
When the character of Christ shall be
perfectly reproduced in his people, then
he will come to claim them as his own.
And here's what I want y'all to
understand.
Right now, we're told that when the
character of Christ I I'm hoping they
can get it up on the screen. I'm not
sure what's going on, but we're told
that Christ is waiting for us to reflect
his character. But here's what's
happening.
We all have different views of the
character of Christ.
So people are are are are reflecting
right Jesus and other people are
reflecting left Jesus and other people
are reflecting black Jesus and other
people are refle reflecting white Jesus.
And so what happens is that the picture
that is forming of Jesus right now is is
a confusing picture.
Before we can get the the character of
Christ reproduced so that when he looks
in the mirror, he sees himself, we all
have to know what Jesus we're
worshiping.
My appeal to you Christians of the
world,
Christians out there in the other
denominations, Christians in our church,
stop reflecting the Jesus you have
created in your own image.
There is not a right Jesus and there is
not a left Jesus. There is Jesus.
There is Jesus.
There is not a black Jesus. There is not
a white Jesus. There is Jesus.
Give me Jesus.
And so right now, I'm going to make a
special appeal.
Right now, I'm going to ask you to get
rid of left Jesus.
And I'm going to ask you who have right
Jesus to make a commitment to get rid of
right Jesus. And what I'm going to do
right now is I'm going to ask you to
respond by putting in the chat L for
today I give up left Jesus and R for
today I give up right Jesus. Please
let's put that in the chat. That's my
appeal. You may not want to out yourself
as who you really believed in left Jesus
or you really believed in right Jesus.
But it's okay.
It's okay. Be like the woman who really
had the son. She was unwilling to let
the body be divided. She was willing to
be seen as wrong that the child might
live. I want you to put that L in the
chat for saying, "Listen, no more left
Jesus for me." R in the chat for saying,
"No more right Jesus for me. I want all
of Jesus." Lord, reintroduce me to who
you are. Help me not to go along with
the painted picture of a right Jesus or
the painted picture of a left Jesus.
Give me Jesus.
Help me to know that I can acknowledge
that racism is a very real thing in the
world today. And also at the same time
say, "Hey, the answer to this is not in
do this to the government to do that."
But in the gospel, help me to know that
I can do those two things. Help me to
know that I can acknowledge that I can
acknowledge that I can acknowledge these
things that are wrong over here, but
also these things that are right over
here. Help me to know that I can be
merciful and loving to the stranger and
also stand up for for what I believe is
right here or there. That two things can
be true at one time.
Help me to stop demonizing
Right Jesus demonizes and left Jesus
demonizes. Help me to understand. Right
Jesus hates his enemies.
Get them. The wicked Democrats. I've
seen I've seen the statements.
How do you call a whole group of people
wicked? How do you do that and be a
Christian?
I believe I believe that that there
there there are church bodies
that are full of error and you will
never hear me say the wicked Catholics
or the wicked Protestants. You'll never
hear that come out my mouth. But we're
comfortable with saying the wicked
Republicans or the wicked Democrats as a
Christian.
You see, right Jesus and left Jesus
are really self-focused.
The actual Jesus
loves people so much that he's willing
to die even for his enemies.
this woman when she said to the king,
"Give her the child." She could have
been killed
because what she was saying to the king
was, "All right, all right. I'm the
guilty one. I'm the guilty one. Yeah.
Yeah. I I stole the child." And she
could have been killed. She was willing
to look like a criminal, like a liar,
like a thief, like a kidnapper.
because her love for the child was so
Listen y'all, I'm I'm closing. I'm
closing. I promise you
what motivated this woman is that the
child had been formed within her.
If it's not your child, you don't care.
If it's not your child, you can be
callous. If it's not your child, you
don't have the same kind of love for it.
This woman was was connected to the
child because it had been formed within
her. Beloved, if Christ is not in you,
you will be content
with a divided body. You will push for a
divided body. You will glorify a divided
body. you will amplify and talk and and
bring up all the things that that show
and that get people on one side of that
divided body. Come on. We got to we got
to be against the other side. There's
going to be a shaking and all that all
those people are going to be shaken out.
Us against them. Us against them. Us
against them. When we have this us
against them mentality, beloved, we are
missing the point.
It is not us against them. Beloved, it
is us against spiritual wickedness in
high places. And our role is to tell the
atheists and to tell the agnostics and
to tell the Protestants and to tell the
Catholics and to tell the people at the
UN and to tell the people in the
government, guess what? The devil is
trying to deceive us all by telling us
it's us versus you, us versus them. Here
is the devil's real plot. But now we're
just getting caught up in left Jesus,
right Jesus, left Jesus, right Jesus,
left Jesus, right Jesus. And we're proud
and we get in our corners with our right
Jesus friends or our left Jesus friends.
We're like, see those left Jesusers,
those right Jesusers, beloved, listen.
Jesus is waiting with longing desire for
the manifestation of himself, not left
Jesus. himself, not white Jesus,
himself, not black Jesus, himself, not
white Jesus. And then when that happens,
he will come to claim his own. Heavenly
Father,
I am praying again that our church
will revisit the past, will write the
wrongs. Lord, if we have to call a
10-day meeting, like I said two weeks
ago, if we have to call a 10-day meeting
where our church comes together and we
address the issues that we have been
sweeping under the rug
for the purpose of uniting the body,
truly uniting the body.
Lord, let it be.
We need a unified front
and we are too busy using the sword to
cut one another in half. Forgive us Lord
for manifesting the spirit of the woman
who said divide it. Let it neither be
mine nor thine but divide it. Forgive us
for worshiping left Jesus, right Jesus,
black Jesus, white Jesus. Lord
give us Jesus
and in his name we pray. Amen. And amen.
May God bless you. May God take this
message
and search our hearts.
and may we bring the body
together the way that the Lord would
have us to do.
God bless you. We're going to put the
chat the the uh the link for the
afterglow discussion. We will be on
Mighty Networks. Uh you are all free to
join us. um we we fellowship, we talk
about the Sabbath school, we talk about
the sermon, and so it's a chance that
everyone gets to um to uh
uh fellowship together. And I'm going to
ask one more thing. If there's any of
you who
do not know Jesus
and you want to get to know him better,
you want to get to understand his word,
you want to get to know Jesus,
I'm going to ask you, we're going to put
this up on the screen if we can.
Want you to connect with our Bible
worker. Um, let's see if we can get that
up in the screen or get it in the link.
If there's anyone that wants to be
baptized because you feel the Lord
calling you to give your life fully to
Christ, I'm going to invite you to reach
out to that same address once we get it
up on the screen. And um and if you just
want to study again to get to know the
word of God better or to give your life
to Christ, reach out
into his everlasting arms. Amen.
>> Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]